<resources>
    <!--Application Name-->
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">N.I Local Amenities Application</string>

    <!--Splash Screen Text Strings-->
    <string name="splash_title" translatable="false">N.I Local Amenities Application</string>

    <!--Area Selection Activity Text Strings-->
    <string name="area_Title" translatable="false">Please select an area of N.I</string>
    <string name="area_AntrimNewtownabbey" translatable="false">Antrim and Newtownabbey</string>
    <string name="area_ArdsAndNorthDown" translatable="false">Ards and North Down</string>
    <string name="area_ArmaghBanbridgeCraigavon" translatable="false">Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon</string>
    <string name="area_BelfastCity" translatable="false">Belfast City</string>
    <string name="area_CausewayAndGlens" translatable="false">Causeway Coast and Glens</string>
    <string name="area_DerryCityAndStrabane" translatable="false">Derry City and Strabane</string>
    <string name="area_FermanaghAndOmagh" translatable="false">Fermanagh and Omagh</string>
    <string name="area_LisburnAndCastlereagh" translatable="false">Lisburn and Castlereagh</string>
    <string name="area_MidAndEastAntrim" translatable="false">Mid and East Antrim</string>
    <string name="area_MidUlster" translatable="false">Mid Ulster</string>
    <string name="area_NewryMourneAndDown" translatable="false">Newry, Mourne and Down</string>

    <!--Council Menu Selections-->
    <string name="CouncilOption_CouncilInformation">Council Information</string>
    <string name="TouristInformation_TouristInformation">Tourist Information</string>

    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Antrim & Newtownabbey Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="antrimnewtownabbey_councilmenu_Title">Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Responsibilities Include: \n\u25CFRegistering of births, deaths, stillbirths, marriages and civil partnership \n\u25CFIssuing authorities for forthcoming marriages \n\u25CFPerforming civil marriages and civil partnerships \n\u25CFProviding general information about registrations to the public \n\nThese services are overseen by the General Register Office (GRO), which holds the majority of registration information for Northern Ireland.</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Antrim Civic Centre Office \nThe office is located in Antrim Civic Centre, \n50 Stiles Way, \nAntrim \nBT41 2UB \nTel: 028 9446 3113 \n\nMossley Mill Office \nThe office is located in Mossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North, \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5AQ \nTel: 028 9034 0179</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">How certificates are obtained has changed. These can no longer be issued from district registration offices. \n\nTo obtain a Birth, Death, Marriage or Civil Partnership (after the initial registration has been complete) contact: \n\nThe General Register Office \nWeb: www.nidirect.gov.uk/gro \nTel: 0300 200 7890 \n\nIn person:General Register Office, NIRSA, Colby House, Stranmilis Court, Belfast, BT9 5RR \n\nCertificates cost £15 for the first and £8 for each additional copy of the same certificate thereafter. Certificates applied for online or by telephone will be posted out within 5 working days. A priority service is available, however, an extra fee will be charged. Please contact GRO for further information.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Antrim and Newtownabbey Borough Councils Building Control team has a responsibility to protect you and the environment and to ensure equal access for all, irrespective of physical ability. \n\nAlthough our role is to enforce Building Regulations, we also give support and advice to ensure that you can meet your obligations under the Building Regulations. Today Building Control service is often involved from the conceptual stage of a project, so that expert opinion on Building Regulation matters is incorporated at the outset. \n\nWhether you are replacing your home heating boiler, building an extension or building a house you will be required to submit an application to Building Control. </string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Building Control for Antrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council is located at: \n\nMossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North, \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5QA \nTel: 028 9034 0140 \nFax: 028 9034 0177 \n(Mon-Fri 9am-5pm)</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Arrange an Inspection \n\nWe will endeavour to visit your property for an inspection on the same day as requested if the inspection booking is made with our office before 10am. \n\nImportant Note: An inspection can be booked as soon as your application has been validated.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Antrim and Newtownabbey Cemetery Opening Times: \nApril - September 8:00am - 10:00pm \nOctober to March 8:00am - 7:00pm \n\nAll our cemetery gates will be locked shut at closing time. \n\nOur cemeteries are open 7 days a week, including all public &amp; bank holidays. \n\nCommemorative Programme \nThe purpose of the Commemorative Programme is to provide members of the public or organisations a means to recognize and honour others through a lasting tribute by the purchase of a tree or bench (subject to conditions) dedicated to that special someone to be planted (or installed) in a park or cemetery. The Programme can also be used by organisations or individuals to sponsor a tree or bench. \n\nIf you require any information regarding the commemorative programme please contact the Leisure Administration team on 02890 340061 or at leisureadmin@antrimandnewtownabbey.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Antrim and Newtownabbey Cemetery Office Opening Times \nMonday to Friday 9.00 am - 4.00 pm. \n\nTelephone enquires will be dealt with Monday to Friday from 9.00 am to 5.00 pm. The office will be closed on Bank Holidays and Public Holidays. \n\nAntrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council is responsible for the general management, regulation and control of the following cemeteries and can provide Information on the Purchase of Burial Rights and for arranging burials and administration. \n\nAntrim (Civic Centre) and Newtownabbey (Mossley Mill) Cemetery Offices: \nMonday - Friday: 9:00am-4:00pm \nAntrim Civic Centre: Tel: 028 9446 3113 \nMossley Mill: Tel: 028 9034 0080</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Antrim Cemetery \nMoylena Road \nAntrim \n\nBelmont Cemetery \nBelmont Road \nAntrim \n\nCranfield Cemetery \nCranfield Road \nRandalstown \n\nCrumlin Cemetery \nCrumlin Road, \nCrumlin \n\nDrummaul Cemetery \nCaddy Road \nRandalstown \n\nMilltown Cemetery \nMilltown Road \nAntrim \n\nMuckamore Cemetery \nOldstone Road \nAntrim \n\nUmgall Cemetery \nUmgall Road \nLylehill \nTemplepatrick \n\nTemplepatrick Cemetery \nCastle Upton \nAntrim Road \nTemplepatrick \n\nCarnmoney East \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney East (ONeill Road Extension) \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney Main \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney Church Yard \nChurch Road, Carnmoney \n\nBallyclare \nDoagh Road B95, Ballyclare \n\nRashee \nSpringvale Road, off Rashee Road B94, Ballyclare \n\nKilbride \nMoyra Road, Doagh, Ballyclare \n\nMallusk \nPark Road, Mallusk</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">The Dogs (NI) Order 1983 requires all dog owners to possess a valid dog licence which must be renewed on an annual basis. This is an essential part of being a responsible dog owner as the dog must be microchipped before a dog licence can be obtained.  This will help Council Officers and local Vets return lost dogs to their owners. \n\nIt is an offence for any person to keep a dog without having a valid dog licence and a fixed penalty notice for £80 may be issued.  Any person found guilty of such an offence shall be liable, on summary conviction, to a fine not exceeding level 3 (£1000).</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Antrim Civic Centre \n50 Stiles Way \nAntrim \nBT41 2UB \nTel: 028 9446 3113 \n\nMossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5QA \nTel: 028 9034 0000</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Our Online Service \nAntrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council have recently introduced Council Direct, a new online service where you can apply for your Dog Licence and renew it online. \n\nAlready using the Online Service? \nResidents within the Borough who previously used the Council’s online facility will still be able to access their Dog Licence information using their previous login username and password for renewal purposes at Council Direct.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Antrim Area Residents: \nUse the online Antrim Bin Checker to see when your Black bin is due for collections. \n\nNewtownabbey Area Residents: \nUse the online Newtownabbey Bin Checker to see when your Black bin is due for collections. Black bins and Brown bins for Newtownabbey residents are collected on the same day once a fortnight. \n\nLeave all bins out by 7:00am on day of collection</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Antrim \nNewpark Household Recycling Centre \nNewpark, Orchard Way, Greystone Road, Antrim \nTel: 028 9442 8107 \n\nBruslee \nBelfast Road, Newtownabbey \n\nCrumlin \nCrumlin Household Recylcing Centre \nRailway Yard, off Main Street, Crumlin \nTel: 028 9442 3640 \n\nONeill Road \nONeill Road Recycling Centre \nONeill Road, Newtownabbey \n\nRandalstown \nCraigmore Household Recycling Centre \nClonkeen Road, Off Church Road, Randalstown \nTel: 028 9447 3813</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Buy a Bin \n\nCharges: \n240ltr Black Bin £30.00 \n240ltr Black Bin £20.00 (Discounted rate) \n240ltr Black Bin £15.00 (Pensioner rate) \n\n180ltr Black Bin £25.00 \n180ltr Black Bin £15.00 (Discounted rate) \n180ltr Black Bin £12.50 (Pensioner rate) \n\nBrown bin:Free \nBlue bin (Antrim only): Free \nKerbie Box (Newtownabbey only): Free \nTriplestack (Newtownabbey only): only available in designated areas (at present out of stock) \nHome Composter: £9.99 \n\nTo purchase a bin: \nIf you live in the Newtownabbey area call us on 028 9034 0056/57.</string>

    <!--Ards and NorthDown Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Ards & Northdown Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="ardsnorthdown_councilmenu_Title">Ards and North Down Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANDCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Ards and North Down Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Ards & North Down Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law all births in Northern Ireland must be registered.  You must register your babys birth within 42 days of the date of birth. You can register a birth in any registrars office in Northern Ireland. \n\nBy law all deaths in Northern Ireland must be registered in Northern Ireland.  A death should be registered as soon as possible to allow funeral arrangements to proceed, but no later than five days from the date of death, except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner. You can register a death at any registrars office in Northern Ireland if the death occurred in Northern Ireland. \n\nYou can choose a civil or a religious wedding.  Civil ceremonies are conducted by the registrar and are non-religious. There are some legal and procedural requirements involved. The Registrar and Deputy Registrars can explain this process.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registrars offices in Ards and North Down are in the council offices at: \n\nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT, telephone 028 9127 8003 \n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP, telephone 028 9182 4003 \n\nOpening hours ​\n\nPlease note that from 1st September 2017 the Registrar’s Office located at Bangor Castle and Church Street, Newtownards will be operating an appointment only system. \n\nTo make an appointment at Bangor Castle please ring 0300 013 3333 ext. 40784 \n\nTo make an appointment at Church Street, Newtownards please ring 0300 013 3333 ext. 40720</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registering a birth \nTo register a birth, you need to fill in a birth registration form. \n\nYou also need certain information to fill in the form: \n\u25CFfull name, surname and sex of the baby \n\u25CFdate and place of birth \n\u25CFfull names, addresses, dates of birth and occupations of the babys mother and father \n\nWhen registering a birth, it is important to give accurate information as a registration cannot be easily changed later. \n\nRegistering a death \nTo register a death, you need to fill in a death registration form with information about the person who died.  This form is available at the registrar’s office. \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be:\n\u25CFaged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17) \n\u25CFunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \n\u25CFfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married \n\u25CFof a different sex \n\nYou must also complete a marriage notice form before your ceremony can take place.  A form is available from the council offices at: \nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT. \n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP </string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">The council is responsible for thousands of building control applications and building inspections every year.  In Building Control we assess plans to make sure they comply with regulations.  As work progresses on site we inspect it at key stages.  It is not the function of Building Control to act as a mediation service between applicant and builder; neither is it to provide a site supervision service, nor to provide a warranty for construction work; these services may be obtained from architects, building surveyors, clerks of works and various warranty schemes.  Building Control service can help designers, builders and the public comply with Northern Ireland Building Regulations. \n\nBuilding Control staff also provide other services, such as the control of dangerous buildings and structures, property searches, postal numbering and providing technical advice.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Contact Building Control \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333 \nEmail: buildingcontrol@ardsandnorthdown.gov.uk \nAddress: Town Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Building control application forms \nAnyone intending to carry out works that would require Building Regulations approval is required to submit either a full plans application or a Building notice application (minor domestic works, including extensions not exceeding 10m2, but not including roofspace) together with the appropriate fee. \n\nBuilding Control offer a pre-submission consultation service, where agents can discuss their outline proposals and seek guidance with regard to means of escape, access for people with disabilities and other issues. \n\nFull plans \nIf the full plan route is chosen, you need to submit: \n\u25CFcompleted full plan application form \n\u25CFduplicate copies of plans \n\u25CFlocation map \n\u25CFsite plan \n\u25CFBuilding notice \n\nThe building notice procedure allows work to be carried out without submitting full plans.  It can be used for the following: \n\u25CFsmall extensions of domestic properties up to 10m2. \n\u25CFstructural alterations of domestic properties. \n\u25CFprovision of services or the installation of fittings in connection with the above. \n\u25CFmaterial change of use of a building to the above \n\nYou cannot use a building control notice for: \n\u25CFindustrial or commercial buildings \n\u25CFerection of houses, flats and maisonettes or roofspace conversions with a floor area over 3m2 \n\nRegularisation \nThis is a procedure, which allows work that was completed without the plans and notices required by Building Regulations being lodged with Building Control.  Such work often comes to light during the sale of a property when the owner is asked to produce evidence of approvals.  When the work complies, or is made to comply with the regulations, which were in operation at the time of completion of the unauthorised work Building Control will issue a “Certificate of Regularisation”.  It can be requested for domestic, industrial or commercial work.</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Headstones \nIf you require a headstone to be put in place, contact a headstone memorial sculptor who can make the necessary arrangements with the council regarding the submission of plans to the Cemeteries Administration Office, 2 Church Street, Newtownards for approval. \n\nCremations \nThere is only one crematorium in Northern Ireland, which is located at Roselawn in Belfast and is under the control of Belfast City Council.  In this case your undertaker will advise you as to how to proceed with arrangements. \nRoselawn Cemetery \n127 Ballygowan Road \nBelfast \nBT5 7UD \nTelephone 028 9044 8288</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Your first contact for funeral enquiries is the undertaker who can make all the arrangements for you, including: \n\u25CFliaising with the council regarding the date and time of burial \n\u25CFopening a grave or buying a new grave \n\nBurials are arranged with the staff in the council offices for cemeteries which are maintained by the council. \n\nThe cemeteries administration office address is 2 Church Street, Newtownards and the telephone numbers are 028 9182 4001 or 028 9182 4002.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">There are different places for burial in Ards and North Down: \n\u25CFBallyvester Cemetery (Donaghadee) \n\u25CFComber Cemetery \n\u25CFGreyabbey New Cemetery \n\u25CFLoughview Cemetery (Comber) \n\u25CFKircubbin Cemetery \n\u25CFKirkistown Cemetery \n\u25CFMovilla Cemetery (Newtownards) \n\u25CFWhitechurch Cemetery (Ballywalter) \n\u25CFClandeboye Cemetery \n\u25CFBangor New Cemetery \n\u25CFRedburn Cemetery (Holywood) \n\u25CFPriory Cemetery (Holywood)</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">It is a legal requirement for all dog owners to register their pet. If this is not done fines can be issued. \n\nApply for a dog licence \nYou can apply for a dog licence online, in person, by post or by telephone. \n\nPay online \nYou need to create an online account. Follow instructions for creating an online account.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">In person \nPlease check the details and return the form with the fee in person to our offices: \n\n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP \nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT \nWe cannot issue a dog licence when you apply in person. \n\nPost \nComplete the form below, sign it and return with the appropriate fee to: \n\nArds and North Down Borough Council \n2 Church Street \nNewtownards \nBT23 4AP \n\nTelephone \nTo pay by debit or credit card, telephone Ards and North Down Borough Council: 0300 013 3333, extension number 40401 or 40418 \n\nIf you need additional information, contact the Borough Inspector. \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333, extension 40401 or 40418</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Microchipping \nAll dogs kept in Northern Ireland must be microchipped before they can be licensed. You must provide a microchip number on the application form for a dog licence. We dont accept a dog licence application without a microchip number.This number must be registered at your current address. \n\nTo find out your dogs microchip number: \n\u25CFask your vet to scan your dog \n\u25CFcontact the organisation that inserted the chip \n\u25CFcontact the Neighbourhood Environment Team who can scan the dog. \n\nAll dog owners must hold a valid licence for their dogs. Your dog must also wear an identity tag, with your name, address and contact telephone number. \n\nIf a veterinary surgeon certifies that inserting a microchip would harm your dogs health, you dont need to microchip your dog. You will need to send us a copy of the vet’s certificate. \n\nFor more information, contact Neighbourhood Environment Team: \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333.</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">The Councils operate roadside recycling schemes for both dry recyclables (blue bins) and food and garden waste (brown bins) and continues to provide extensive facilities at Waste Recycling Centres for recycling a range of materials. \n\nIn addition to the facilities at the Waste Recycling Centres, there are numerous bin bank facilities for recycling glass containers and textiles.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">N/A</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Reduce pressure on your grey bin by maximising the materials you can recycle in your blue and green or brown bin.  Use your blue bin to recycle certain clean paper, cardboard, aluminium and plastic products as listed below. Use your brown or green bin for food waste and garden waste such as grass clippings, weeds, leaves and tree branches or twigs. You dont need a green and a brown bin as both bins are used to recycle the same materials.</string>

    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="armaghbanbridgecraigavon_councilmenu_Title">Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ABCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law all births occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered. This should be done within 42 days of the date of the birth at any District Registrar’s Office in Northern Ireland. \n\nBy law all deaths occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered. This should be done within 5 days from the date the death occurred except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner. \n\nTo get married you must give a minimum of 28 days notice otherwise you may need to postpone your marriage. It is recommended time period is 8 to 10 weeks, however you can give notice up to a year before the date of your marriage.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Armagh Registration Office \nAddress: The Palace Demesne, Armagh, BT60 4EL \nTelephone: 028 3752 9615 \nEmail: jennifer.coulter@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening Hours: by appointment only \nMonday to Thursday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4.30pm \nFriday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4pm \nPlease contact the office by phone or email to arrange an appointment. \n\nBanbridge Registration Office \nAddress The Civic Building, Downshire Road, Banbridge, BT32 3JY \nTelephone: 028 4066 0614 \nEmail: elaine.gilmour@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening hours: by appointment only \nMonday to Thursday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4.30pm \nFriday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4pm \n\nPlease contact the office by telephone to arrange an appointment. \n\nCraigavon Registration Office \nAddress: Craigavon Civic and Conference Centre, Lakeview Road, Craigavon BT64 1AL \nTelephone: 028 3831 2440 or 028 3831 2441 \nEmail: registrar@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening hours: \nYou do not need an appointment, as a queuing system is in operation, however waiting times will vary. \nMonday to Thursday: 9am-12.30pm (last entrance at 12.15pm) and 2pm-4.30pm (last entrance at 4.15pm) \nFriday: 9am–12.30pm (last entrance at 12.15pm) and 2pm–4pm (last entrance at 3.45pm)</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register a birth? \n\nWhere the parents are married: \nThe following people can register a child’s birth: \nThe mother or father of the child \nThe grandmother, grandfather, aunt, uncle of the child who has knowledge of the information required to register the birth \nThe occupier of the premises in which the child was born \nAny person present at the birth \nAny person having charge of the child \n\nWhere the parents are not married to each other: \nThe name of the father will only be recorded on the birth certificate if both parents are in attendance or attend separately to sign the registration. \nIf either parent is unavailable, please contact the Registrar’s Office for further information. \n\nThe following people can also register a child’s birth: \nMaternal grandmother, maternal grandfather, maternal aunt or maternal uncle of the baby who has knowledge of the information required to register a birth \n\nWho can register a death? \nAny relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register \nAny person present at the death \nA person taking care of the funeral arrangements \nThe Executor or Administrator of the deceased’s estate \nThe occupier (governor, matron, superintendent or other Chief Officer) at the time of death of the premises \nA person finding, or taking charge of, the body \n\nLegal requirements \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be: \nAged 18 years old or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either party are aged 16 or 17 years old) \nUnrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \nFree to marry, for example, neither of you are already married or in a civil partnership \nOf a different sex \nCapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of consenting to the marriage</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Most people realise that they may need approval for their proposed building work but don’t always understand the difference between building regulations and planning permission.  You might need one or the other, both, or neither, but you must find out before you start any work. \n\nPlanning is interested in the way our towns, cities and countryside is developed. This includes the appearance of buildings, the use of land &amp; landscaping considerations, highway access and the impact that the development will have on the general environment.  Planning permission is NOT usually required for most internal alterations, for some extensions, some loft conversions or some garages. \n\nBuilding Regulations deal mainly with health and safety matters in the interest of the people who will use the building.  They also include requirements to ensure that fuel and power is conserved and facilities are provided for people, including those with disabilities, to access and move around inside buildings. \n\nIf you are in any doubt about whether you need to apply for planning permission or building regulations approval, please check with us before you start any work.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Our planning office, located at \n\nBridgewater House, \n23a Castlewellan Road, \nBanbridge, \nCo. Down \nBT32 4AX</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">If you are planning to carry out work, check with us before you start to see if you need building regulations approval. \n\nSome work may also require planning permission, so you should also check with our Planning Service before you begin. \n\nThere are 3 ways to apply: \n\u25CFFull plans application – for proposed work to domestic and non domestic \n\u25CFBuilding notice application – for works of a minor nature to domestic properties. \n\u25CFRegularisation application – for work that has already been carried out to a domestic or non-domestic property without getting approval at the time (retrospective approval of unauthorised work)</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Every effort is made to accommodate individual memorial wishes of families, however, it is necessary to ensure that the size and type of memorials are appropriate to their setting. Therefore all memorials (headstones) must be approved by the Cemeteries Office prior to erection, including the proposed inscription. Please note emblems are not permitted on headstones. </string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">We operate and maintain the following cemeteries: \nAghagallon Cemetery, Rock Lane, Aghagallon \nBallynahone Cemetery, Ballynahonemore Road, Armagh \nBanbridge Cemetery, Newry Road, Banbridge \nDonaghcloney Cemetery, Main Street, Donaghcloney \nDromore New Cemetery, Mound Road, Dromore \nDrumadonnell Cemetery, Dromara Road, Ballyroney \nKernan Cemetery, Kernan Hill Road, Kernan, Portadown \nLurgan Cemetery, New Line, Lurgan \nLynastown Cemetery, Bluestone Road, Portadown \nMagheralin Cemetery, Newforge Road, Magheralin \nOld Annaclone Cemetery, Church Hill Road, Annaclone \nSeagoe Cemetery, Seagoe Road, Portadown \nSeapatrick Cemetery, Church Square, Banbridge \nShankill Cemetery, Shankill Street, Lurgan \nThe Orchard Cemetery, Corcreevy Road, Richhill \n\nWe appreciate that preparing funeral arrangements is a difficult time for families and we try to be as helpful as possible during this time.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">When a grave is purchased, the buyers name and address is entered in to the register as the titleholder for the specified plot and they receive a title deed certificate. \n\nThe titleholder of the burial plot is then given the right to up to three internments (burials) per plot.  The purchase of the plot does not mean that the person has purchased the land, only the right to internment. \n\nWe can only accept a request for an internment from the titleholder and can only grant permission to the titleholder for the erection of memorials. \n\nBurial plots cannot be purchased in advance of a death.</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">Everybody who owns a dog must have a dog licence (exceptions apply see below). It is a requirement that dogs are microchipped in order to apply for a dog licence. A microchipping service is provided by your local Vet, please contact them for further information.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">If you need advice or guidance on which dog licence you need, please call 0300 0300 900 or ehealth@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">You do not need a license for the following: \n\u25CFa puppy under six months old and kept by the person who was also the keeper of the bitch that gave birth to the puppy \n\u25CFan assistance dog used by a disabled person \n\u25CFa dog kept, and on offer for sale, in a licensed pet shop \n\u25CFa police dog \n\u25CFa dog kept under a block licence, on the premises to which the block licence relates</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">You can only order ONE of each type of bin. \n\nYou can order a bin by telephone on 0300 0300 900, by calling into any of our depots or through the Bin-Ovation App. \n\nPlease note: you may only leave out one bin of each colour for collection.  Bin crews will not empty unapproved additional bins.  If you already have a bin and wish to order an extra one due to exceptional circumstances you will need to request an additional/larger bin assessment application. For more information click here. \n\nCancellations \nTo cancel your order, call us on 0300 0300 900.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Armagh: Station Road Industrial Estate, Station Road, Armagh, BT61 7NP \nKeady: Unit 17, Keady Business Centre, Annvale Road, Keady, BT60 2RP \nMarkethill: Unit 5, Markethill Business Centre, Fairgreen, Markethill, BT60 1PW \nTandragee: Madden Road, Tandragee, BT62 2DG \nBanbridge: Scarva Road, Banbridge, BT32 3QD \nDromore: Mossvale Road, Dromore, BT25 1DG \nRathfriland: Iveagh Park  Road, Rathfriland, BT34 5DZ \nPortadown: Fairgreen Recycling Centre, Duke Street, Portadown, BT62 3EX \nLurgan: New Line Recycling Centre, Tandragee Road, Lurgan, BT66 8TA</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">If you would like to dispose of large household items, such as a sofa, cooker, bed, washing machine, fridge or freezer, you can request a bulky waste collection. \n\nThere is a non-refundable charge of £6 per lift of up to 3 bulky household items. \n\nWe will lift \nFurniture	table, chairs, suites, beds, cabinets, carpet/lino, TV, \nWhite goods	fridge, freezer, cooker, tumble dryer, washing machine, microwave, \nGarden equipment	lawnmower, garden implements, summer seat, garden tables/chairs \n\nWe won’t lift \nWood	Sheds, fences, skirting boards, architraves, gripper rods, broken up furniture, dog kennels \nMetal	Iron bars, corrugated iron, garage doors, gates \nDIY materials	Bricks, blocks, concrete, pipes, guttering, plasterboard \nFixtures &amp; fittings	Fireplaces, kitchens, bathroom suites, doors, radiators, storage heaters, water cylinders/tanks, heating systems, stair bannisters, windows, slide robes, glass front fires \nOther	Oil tanks, gas cylinders, car parks, concrete coal bunkers, pianos \n\nThe list is not exhaustive and advice on other items can be obtained from calling on 0300 0300 900 .</string>

    <!--Belfast City Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Belfast Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="belfastcity_councilmenu_Title">Belfast City Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="BCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Belfast City Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Belfast City Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law, your babys birth must be registered within 42 days of the date of birth. This is free and can be done in any District Registrars office in Northern Ireland. \n\nOur Registrars office is located in Belfast City Hall \n\nBy law, all deaths occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered no later than five days from when the death occurred (except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner). \n\nMarriage notice \nYou must give a minimum of 28 days notice to get married. If you dont give 28 days notice, you may need to postpone your marriage. You can give notice up to a year before the date of your marriage.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Our office opening hours are: \nMonday to Thursday 	9.30am to 4.30pm 	Last entrance to registration is 4.15pm \nFriday	9.30am to 4pm	Last entrance to registration is 3.45pm \nSaturday and Sunday 	Closed \n\nRegistrars office \nBelfast City Hall \nBelfast \nBT1 5GS \n\nPhone: 028 9027 0274</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">How to register a birth \nYou will need to fill in a birth registration form. This is usually completed by the  person registering the birth (normally the childs mother). \n\nWho can register? \nThe mother or father of the baby, if you are a married couple \ngrandfather or grandmother \nuncle or aunt \noccupier of the premises where the baby was born \nany person present at the childs birth \nany person who has charge of the child. \n\nIn the case of a child born to an unmarried couple, the details of the father may be recorded if: \nboth parents attend and sign the registration form together, or \na declaration of paternity is produced\n\nRegistering a death\nWho can register?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceaseds estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nLegal requirements \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be: \naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17) \nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married \nof a different sex.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">We are responsible for delivering planning functions in Belfast. This involves:\nreceiving and making decisions on the majority of planning applications\nenforcing breaches of planning permission\nmaking tree preservation orders\nprotecting and preserving built heritage\nproducing a local development plan outlining how land should be used and developed in the future.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Our public office, located at 4-10 Linenhall Street, is open from 9am - 5pm, Monday to Friday.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">How we make planning decisions\nThe type, size and complexity of an application will determine how a decision is made. There are three ways in which a decision can be made:\n\nOur Planning Committee will consider all major applications.\nA planning officer has the authority to determine smaller, more straightforward applications.\nAn elected member may request that an application is decided by the Planning Committee, provided they give sound planning reasons for doing so.\nThe Department of the Environment will make decisions that have regional significance.\nOur Scheme of Delegation (PDF - 75KB) sets out full details.\n\nEnforcement\nWe can take enforcement action against breaches of planning controls where:\nbuilding work which needs planning permission is undertaken without approval,\nconditions attached to a planning condition are not complied with, or\nthe use of a building or site is changed without planning permission.\nIf any planning controls are breached, we will investigate. Planning enforcement is a complex area and the legal processes involved can be lengthy and complicated. An instant response or resolution cannot be guaranteed.\n\nFor more information on how we deal with enforcement complaints and our service standards please read our Enforcement Customer Charter.\n\nRequest to speak to committee\nIf you would like to speak to our planning committee about a planning application, please complete the form below. You need to have the application reference number and you must submit the request at least 48 hours before the committee meeting. You can only speak to committee if youve submitted a written response to an application.\n\nOnce we receive your application we will be in touch with more information.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Cemeteries\nBurials can take place in four of our cemeteries - Roselawn, Dundonald, Knockbreda and Belfast City Cemetery.\n\nHeritage project at the City Cemetery\nWith funding from the Heritage and Lottery Fund (NI)’s Parks for People Programme, we’d like to develop a programme to protect, enhance and promote the rich heritage of City Cemetery.\n\nBereavement Services\nOur Bereavement Services Office is located on the Ground Floor, Cecil Ward Building, 4-10 Linenhall Street, Belfast, BT2 8BP.\nOur phone number is 028 9027 0296.\n\nContact our Bereavement Services Office if you have a query about our cemeteries. </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Office opening hours \nMonday and Friday 	8.30am - 4pm \nTuesday, Wednesday and Thursday 	9am - 4pm \nSaturday 	8.30am - 11.30am \n\nTel: 028 9027 0296 \n\nGround Floor \nCecil Ward Building \n4-10 Linenhall Street \nBelfast \nBT2 8BP </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">About our cemeteries \nRoselawn is currently the only cemetery with new burial plots available. \n\nThere are no new grave plots available in either Dundonald or Belfast City Cemetery, but burials can still take place in existing graves.\n\nCremations are conducted at City of Belfast Crematorium.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">All dogs must have a valid licence and wear identification with the name and address of their keeper, either on a tag or engraved on a collar plate. We no longer issue coloured dog tags with new licences; owners must supply the identification themselves.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">We have moved\n\nOur customer reception has moved to the ground floor of The Cecil Ward Building.\n\nOur new address is:\nDog Wardens\nGround Floor\nThe Cecil Ward Building\n4-10 Linenhall Street\nBelfast\nBT2 8BP</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">You do not need to license your dog if it is:\na puppy under six months old and kept by the person who is also the keeper of the puppys mother,\nan assistance dog used by a disabled person, or\na police dog.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Bin and box collections\n\nPlease recycle as much as possible to avoid over-filling your general waste bin.\n\nWe have two types of collection in Belfast:\nIf you have a general waste bin, a recycling bin and compost bin:\nAll bins are collected fortnightly - recycling bin one week, general waste and compost bin the next week.\nIn most cases, your collection day is the same each week.\nIf you have a purple glass recycling box it may be collected on a different day to your wheeled recycling bin.\nIf you have a general waste bin, red and black recycling boxes and a green food waste bin:\nYour general waste bin is collected fortnightly.\nYour recycling boxes and food waste are collected weekly (on the same day).\nYour collection day will be the same day of the week as your general waste collection. </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">We have four centres you can use for recycling household waste. They are all free to use. Please note, we cannot accept commercial waste.\n\nAlexandra Park Avenue - 180 Alexandra Park Avenue, BT15 3GJ\n\nBlackstaff Way - 1 Blackstaff Way, BT11 9DT\n\nOrmeau - 6 Park Road, BT7 2FX\n\nPalmerston Road - 2-4 Palmerston Road, BT4 1QA</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Using your bin\n\nPlease remember:\nAlways leave your bin out by 7am, and keep it out until 8pm if it has not been collected.\nLeave it at your bin collection point and return it to your property after collection.\nDont overfill your bin - make sure the lid closes properly.\nDont leave waste next to your bin as we can not collect it and you risk an £80 fine (see exception below).\nIf using a wheelie bin liner, make sure you remove it from the rim of your bin before collection.\nDont put electrical or bulky items in your bin. Instead book a bulky collection.\nKeep your bin clean, disinfected and in good repair.\nDont put waste in or take waste out of a bin you dont own or control.\nWe will only collect one general waste bin per property, unless there are exceptional circumstances, where:\nthere are six or more people living in the property, or\nsomeone with a medical condition in the property requires another bin for their waste.\nRemember, we can not collect side or bagged waste left beside bins or in entries; this is littering and you could be fined £80. </string>

    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Causeway Glens Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="causewaycoastglens_councilmenu_Title">Causeway Coast and Glens Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="CCGCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Information booklets &amp; leaflets are available at the Registration Reception. Forms are available to the Public for Name changes, Adoptions, Re-registrations, Marriage and Civil Partnership Application, Birth and Death registration.\n\nEach office can only provide certificates for a Birth, Death, Marriage or Civil Partnership when you are registering the event.  You can order certificates for previously registered events in one of the following ways:\nOnline: www.nidirect.gov.uk\nTelephone: 0300 200 7890\nPost: Ask a member of staff for an application form\nIn Person: The General Register Office (GRO), Colby House, Stranmillis Court, Belfast BT9 5RR</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Office opening hours are:\nMonday – Friday: 9.30 am – 12.30 pm and 2.00 pm – 4.30 pm (Ballycastle Office open morning only)\n\nBank and Public Holidays excepted.\n\nAn appointments system operates.\n\nContact Details -\nBallycastle:\nSheskburn House, 7 Mary Street, Ballycastle BT54 6QH\nTel 028 2076 2225\nEmail: stephanie.mclaughlin@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nBallymoney:\nRiada House, 14 Charles Street, Ballymoney, BT53 6DZ\nTel: 028 2766 0200\nEmail: janet.mccaughey@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nColeraine:\nCloonavin, 66 Portstewart Road, Coleraine, BT52 1EY\nTel: 028 7034 7034\nEmail: gwyneth.kerr@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\nEmail: elaine.kane@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nLimavady:\n7 Connell Street, Limavady, Bt49 OHA\nTel: 028 7772 2226\nEmail: monica.anderson@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">GRO holds records from 1845 for non-Roman Catholic marriages and 1 January 1864 onwards for all marriages, births and deaths. \n\nCauseway Coast and Glens Borough Council Registration Offices are located in Ballycastle, Ballymoney, Coleraine and Limavady.</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">If you intend to erect, alter or extend a building, to install services, fittings or works to a building, or to materially change the use of a building, you must first seek approval to do so from your district council.   There are three ways to apply for building regulations approval with a set fee allocated to each:\nFull Plans Submission - for proposed work to dwellings and non-domestic properties\nBuilding Notice Application - for small/minor work to an existing dwelling\nRegularisation Application - for work that has already been carried out to a dwelling or non-domestic property without getting prior approval</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Ballycastle Office\nSheskburn House\n7 Mary Street\nBallycastle\nBT54 6QH\n\nBallymoney Office\nRiada House\n14 Charles Street\nBallymoney\nBT53 6DZ\nTel: 028 2766 0251, 028 2766 0253\n\nColeraine Office\nCloonavin\n66 Portstewart Road\nColeraine\nBT52 1EY\nTel: 028 7034 7252\n\nLimavady Office\n7 Connell Street\nLimavady\nBT49 0HA\nTel:   028 7776 0301</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">The Building Control Department is there to offer you professional help and impartial advice on your project and to answer any queries you may have on regulatory issues.  There are works that are exempt from requiring an application. We can provide confirmation of exemption from the Building Regulations if a request is received in writing together with a fee of £25.</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">The Estates Service is responsible for the operation and upkeep of cemeteries and Old Graveyards.  These facilities are situated at the following locations.  If you have any queries regarding opening hours or facilities, see below for contact details. \n\nInformation on the purchase of grave plots can be obtained from the Registrar of Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages\n\nAgherton Cemetery, Agherton Road, Portstewart\nBallymoney Cemetery, Knock Road, Ballymoney\nBallywillan Cemetery, Magherabuoy Road, Portrush\nColeraine Cemetery, Portrush Road, Coleraine\nEnagh Cemetery, Scroggy Road, Limavady\nKilrea Cemetery, Blackrock Road, Kilrea\nPortstewart Cemetery, Coleraine Road, Portstewart\nRasharkin Cemetery, Finvoy Road, Rasharkin</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Contact Us\nIf you would like further information, please contact us\n\nTel: 028 2766 0200\nEmail: info@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">“Old Graveyards” refer to the graveyards at:\nAghanloo, Limavady\nAgherton Old, Portrush\nAgivey, Coleraine\nArdclinnis, Glenariff\nBallylintagh, Coleraine\nBallywillan, Portrush\nBanagher, Limavady\nBonamargy, Ballycastle\nBovevagh Limavady\nCamus, Coleraine\nDerrykeighan, Ballymoney\nDesertoghill, Garvagh\nGlenariff Road\nGlenullin, Garvagh\nDownhill, Castlerock\nDunluce, Portrush\nKilraughts, Ballymoney\nLayde, Cushendall\nLoughan, Coleraine\nPriory, Limavady\nQueen Street, Ballymoney\nRamoan, Ballycastle\nTamlaght Finlagan, Limavady\nTemplastragh, Port Bradden\nThe Knockans, Ballymoney\nVow, Ballymoney\nWalworth, Limavady</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">If you keep or own a dog you must obtain a licence for the dog from the Council.\n\nYou cannot obtain a licence for the dog unless the dog has been microchipped. You will need to provide this microchip number when applying for a licence.</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">To apply for a licence you will need to visit your local council offices and enquire about this at reception</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Exemptions For Needing a Dog Licence\na puppy under six months old and kept by the person who is also the keeper of the mother that gave birth to the puppy\nan assistance dog used by a disabled person\na police dog</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">If you have any queries or require further information on Councils recycling services, please e-mail us at recycle@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">If you wish to purchase a new bin, wheels or axle, please contact your local Council office:-\n\nBallymoney  028 2766 0222\nColeraine     028 7034 3453\nLimavady     028 7776 0305\nMoyle           028 2076 2225</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Causeway Coast and Glens Borough Council operate a fully engineered facility at Craigahulliar Landfill Site, Ballymacrea Road, Portrush, BT56 8NS.\n\nLicensed to take:\nHousehold/Domestic Waste\nCommercial Waste\nIndustrial Waste</string>

    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Derry Strabane Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="derrystrabane_councilmenu_Title">Derry and Strabane Council Information</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="DSCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Welcome to the District Registration Service.  The primary function of the Registration Offices is to register Births, Stillbirths, Deaths, Marriages and Civil Partnerships, to issue authorities for forthcoming Marriages and Civil Partnerships and to officiate at Civil Marriage Ceremonies and Civil Partnership Ceremonies/Registrations, to issue certified copies and give general information to the public about these matters.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Derry/Londonderry Office operate by appointment or customer call-in system at 14 Magazine Street, BT48 6HH. Call us on 02871 376520 or email michelle.duddy@derrystrabane.com\n\nThe Strabane Office OPERATE BY APPOINTMENT ONLY at Council Offices, 47 Derry Road, Strabane, Co Tyrone BT82 8DY. Call us on 02871 253253 Ext 4209 or email michelle.duddy@derrystrabane.com.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Both offices currently open to the public 9:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. and 2:00 p.m. to 4:30 p.m, Monday to Friday and carry out Civil Marriage and Civil Partnership Ceremonies outside these hours by prior arrangement.  There is also service provision available out-of-hours for emergency Death Registration.  Please contact your Funeral Director who will advise.</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Building Control has a statutory duty to enforce building regulations to ensure minimum standards of Health &amp; Safety apply to all buildings.\n\nThe main services provided by the Building Control Department are:\nExamination of applications submitted under the Building Regulations (NI) 2012\nInspection of building work on site\nProvision of information for Property Certificate enquiries\nReporting on applications made for Entertainment Licences\nProviding advice on Building Regulations and associated matters.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">For further information and queries contact:\n\nBuilding Control\nTelephone: (028) 71 253253\nEmail: info@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Changes to the Building Regulations regarding Building Notice applications.\nFrom October 31st 2012 a Building Notice application cannot be accepted for the following work:-\n•    The erection of a dwelling\n•    The increase of the floor area of a dwelling by more than 10m2\n•    The creation of a new storey with a floor area greater than 3m2\n•    The conversion of roof space to habitable accommodation\n•    Domestic garages greater than 30m2</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Active Cemeteries Opening Times:\nSpring / Summer (1st May – 30th September)\nMonday to Sunday 8.00 am to 7.00 pm\n\nAutumn Winter (1st October – 30th April)\nMonday to Sunday 8.00 am to 4.30 pm</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">All enquiries relating to Cemeteries/Graveyards to:\n\nCity Cemetery Office,\nGatelodge,\nLone Moor Road,\nDerry\nBT48 9LA\nTel : 028 71362615\nEmail : grainne.murray@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">N/A</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">All dogs, with the exception of guide dogs, must have a valid licence. Before you get a dog or a puppy you MUST get a licence for it. It is against the law not to. A puppy that stays with its mother must have a licence by the age of six months.\n\nIt should be noted that since April 2012 it is no longer possible to licence a dog without including a valid microchip number for your dog. Microchipping is a simple, safe modern identification method which is permanent and can not be removed, so even if someone steals your dog we can still trace it by its microchip.\n\nDogs must also wear an identity disc or tag, stating the owners name, address and contact telephone number.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Dog Control\nDerry City and Strabane District Council\n47 Derry Road\nStrabane\nBT82 8DY\nTel: 028 71253253 \n\nEnvironmental Health Department\nDerry City and Strabane District Council  \n98 StrandRoad,\nDerry Strabane\nBT48 7NN\nTel: 028 71253253  </string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">A dog’s licence offers some proof of ownership. Under the Dogs (NI) Order 1983 as amended, it is a legal requirement that anyone in possession of a dog must hold a valid licence. As the details of dog owner and dog are officially registered with the Council, each owner who registers his or her dog with their local Council is issued with a licence. Owners are reminded that their dog must wear a collar with an identity disc or tag attached to it.  This tag or disc must state the owner`s name, address and contact telephone number.</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">The black or grey wheeled bin is the general waste bin. It can be used to dispose of general household waste that is not permitted in either the Blue or Brown Bin. Waste from the black bin typically goes to landfill which is expensive and has an impact on the environment, so Council encourage people to recycle as much as possible using our Blue Bin recycling service or Brown Bin / Caddy food waste collection service.\n\nThe blue wheeled bin is for recycling waste. This helps Council make savings on disposing of waste which means we can do more for you and your family, as well as helping the environment.\n\nDerry City and Strabane District Council now offer food waste collection services to households in the Council district. This new service means we spend less money on dealing with food waste and we can spend more on services for you and your family. It will also help the environment by reducing harmful emissions from landfill.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">DIRECT HELPLINE FOR WASTE &amp; RECYCLING:\nCall (028) 71 374 107\n\nISSUES WITH REFUSE OR BULKY WASTE COLLECTIONS:\nEmail or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 3435\n\nSTREET CLEANSING:\nEmail Street Cleansing  or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6828\n\nENFORCEMENT:\nEmail Enforcement or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6868​\n\nLITTER BINS / DOG BINS / COMMUNITY CLEAN UPS:\nEmail or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6807</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Frequently Asked Questions\n\nQ. What if my bin is not serviced?\nA. If council is unable to service your bin because of operational difficulties attempts will be made to collect it within 24 hours of the scheduled collection date – or on the next working day if your collection day is a Friday.\n\nQ. How many bins can each household leave out for collection?\nA. Council, under normal circumstances, will only collect one bin per household.  Council can arrange to collect additional bins where special circumstances apply i.e. those with medical conditions etc.  Further information on additional bins can be obtained by contacting 028 7137 4017.\n\nQ. Will the operative collect, empty and return my bin as I am physically unable to do so?\nA. Council can arrange to collect, empty and return bins for those residents who are physically unable to do so.  Further information on this scheme can be obtained by contacting 028 7137 4107 or by e-mailing brian.mckenna@derrystrabane.com or ian.lamrock@derrystrabane.com\n\nQ. How can I report any difficulties or complaints?\nA. If you experience any difficulty or problems with any aspects of the service provided, you should contact the Customer Support Services at the City Engineers Department on 028 7137 4107 to register your problem or complaint so that the appropriate action can be taken.</string>

    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Fermanagh Omagh Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="fermanaghomagh_councilmenu_Title">Fermanagh and Omagh Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="FOCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Registrar’s Office is one of 11 district registration offices in Northern Ireland whose primary function is to register births, deaths, marriages and civil partnerships.\n\nIt also performs civil marriages and partnerships at approved venues and provides general information to the public.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Opening Hours:\nMonday – Thursday 9.30am – 4.30pm\nFriday  9.30am – 4.00pm\nClosed 12.30pm – 1.30pm\n\nIt is advisable to arrive 15 minutes before closure times.\n\nThe registration service for Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is delivered from both the Grange in Omagh, and the Townhall in Enniskillen.\nTelephone:  0300 303 1777</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Councils in Northern Ireland have a statutory duty to enforce the Building Regulations and they do this through their Building Control Department. The Building Regulations are designed to ensure certain standards of health and safety apply to all buildings, with particular focus on achieving adequate standards of fire safety.  The regulations also protect the environment by requiring buildings to be thermally efficient, reducing energy consumption and therefore the emission of pollutants which damage the atmosphere. Regulations are also in place to deal with accessibility and are effective in improving the quality of life for people with disabilities. Building Regulations and Building Control, therefore, have an important role to play in helping protect people and the environment</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">The Building Control Department, Fermanagh and Omagh District Council\nTel: 0300 303 1777\nEmail: buildingcontrol@fermanaghomagh.com</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council’s Building Control Department provide the following services:\nEnergy Performance in buildings\nPostal naming and numbering\nProperty Certificates\nBuilding Regulations\nDangerous Structures\nEntertainment Licensing\n\nThrough these services the Building Control Department works closely with architects, agents, those involved in construction, members of the legal profession as well as members of the public.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is responsible for five Municipal cemeteries in the District.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">The locations are as follows:-\nCross Cemetery, located adjacent to the Irvinestown Road (but accessible through Carran Industrial Estate) in Enniskillen, BT74 4RN\nGreen Hill Cemetery, Gortin Rd, Omagh BT79 7HT\nFintona Cemetery, Tattymoyle/Lisdergan Rd, Fintona, Co. Tyrone\nBreandrum Cemetery, Tempo Rd, Enniskillen, BT74 6HR\nDublin Rd Cemetery, 112 Dublin Rd, Omagh, BT78 1TT.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Breandrum Cemetery in Enniskillen and the Dublin Rd Cemetery in Omagh are both closed cemeteries. Only new plots for the burial of a child are available for purchase in Breandrum.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">The Dogs (NI) Order 1983 requires all dog owners to possess a valid dog licence which must be renewed on an annual basis. This is an essential part of being a responsible dog owner as the dog must be microchipped before a dog licence can be obtained.  This will help Council Officers and local Vets return lost dogs to their owners.\n\nIt is an offence for any person to keep a dog without having a valid dog licence and a fixed penalty notice for £80 may be issued.  Any person found guilty of such an offence shall be liable, on summary conviction, to a fine not exceeding level 3 (£1000).</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Please visit the website at: https://council.direct/ to register your dog.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Changes in Dog Licensing Legislation regarding Licence Tags\n\nDue to recent changes in Dog Licensing and Identification Regulations, from the 1st January 2015 Dog Licence Tags will be abolished and will not be provided with a Dog Licence.  This decision has been taken by Central Government (DARD) and therefore local Councils must be in full compliance.  It will still however be a legal requirement to have the keeper’s details attached to the collar on a plate or badge.\n\nConcessionary dog licence applications and renewals.\n\nConcessionary dog licence applications cannot be made online as proof of concession must be provided to the Dog Licensing Department before the licence can be issued.  Concessionary Licences for sterilized dogs and persons over 65 licensing their first dog, who have previously provided proof of concession, can be renewed online as the concessionary status will not have changed.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is responsible for waste management, including refuse collection and bulky waste.\n\nThe Council provides a refuse collection service to all domestic households as well as a collection service to commercial and industrial premises. The Council actively promotes community engagement in the separation of waste at source by utilising the mixed collection service provided by the Council.\n\nWe have state of the art recycling facilities at Drummee outside Enniskillen and Gortrush on the edge of Omagh. In addition there are Recycling Centres in the following locations across the district.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Alternatively, opening times are as follows:\n· Drummee, Enniskillen: Monday-Friday, 9am-6pm, Saturday, 9am-4pm\n· Gortrush, Omagh: Monday-Friday, 8.30am-6.45pm, Saturday, 9am-6.45pm\n· Belleek: Monday, Wednesday Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-3pm\n· Carrickmore: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Dromore: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Fintona: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Garrison: Tuesday, Thursday 10am-6pm, Saturday 3.30pm-5.30pm\n· Irvinestown: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Kesh: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pmn· Kinawley: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Lisbellaw: Monday, Tuesday Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Lisnaskea: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Newtownbutler: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Rosslea: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Tempo: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-5.30pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Keep up to date by downloading the Bin-Ovation app\n\nYou can keep up to date by downloading the Bin-Ovation app, a new App that is revolutionising recycling for households and local Councils across Northern Ireland.\n\nFree to download, Bin-ovation gives you absolute clarity on how to treat hundreds of household waste items and gives instant access to waste and recycling information.\n\nAvailable on smart phones and tablets the bin-ovation app provides:\nClarity on over 300 household items including which bin the item should be placed in or if you can take it to your local recycling centre\nCalendar and a set reminder of which day your bin is collected to ensure you present the right bin at the kerbside for collection\nOpening hours and GPS directions to your local recycling centres\nNews on your current and new collections including up to date information on daily changes to services\nInformation on your recycling services and tips on how to reduce, reuse and recycle</string>

    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Lisburn Castlereagh Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="lisburncastlereagh_councilmenu_Title">Lisburn and Castlereagh Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="LCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registration services for Births, Marriages and Civil Partnerships are available at the Councils headquarters at Lagan Valley Island, Lisburn and also at its Council Offices at Bradford Court, Galwally.\n\nIn view of the nature of the services offered, customer demand can be difficult to predict and there may be periods of high demand where customers may be required to wait to see the first available Registrar/Deputy Registrar. We would ask for your patience and understanding in this regard.\n\nTo facilitate the  process, please read over the information which has been compiled to assist you accessing our registration services.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Lisburn Registration Office\nRegistration Office, Island Civic Centre, The Island, Lisburn, BT27 4RL\nTel: 028 9250 9262/3 or 028 9250 9488\nEmail: bdm.registration@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nOpening Hours\nMonday - Friday\n9.00am to 12.45pm\n1.30pm to 4.30pm (Closing at 4.00pm on the first Wednesday of each month)\n\nYou do not need an appointment to visit Lisburn Registration Office, though please note that a queuing system is in operation. Customers should arrive at least 45 minutes before the stipulated closing times. However Registration Staff deal with very sensitive issues and waiting times will vary.\n\nPlease note Mondays and Fridays are extremely busy days and longer waiting times may apply.  On occasions you may be asked to return.  If your visit to the Lisburn Office is not urgent you may prefer to call on a Tuesday, Wednesday or Thursday.\n\nCastlereagh Registration Office\nCastlereagh Registration Office is now operating an appointment system.  To make an appointment please use the contact details below.\n\nRegistration Office, 1 Bradford Court, Upper Galwally, Castlereagh, BT8 6RB\nTel: 028 9244 7822 or 028 9250 9270\nEmail: RegBradfordCourt@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nOpening Hours\nMonday - Friday\n9.30am to 12.30pm\n2.00pm to 4.30pm (closes 4.00pm on Friday)</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">The aim of the Building Control Service is to deliver a customer orientated quality service to architects, designers, developers, builders, solicitors and the general public, and as such ensure a safer and healthier built environment for all.\n\nAs well as enforcing the application of The Building Regulations, the Building Control Service has a responsibility for Street Naming, Dangerous Buildings legislation, Energy Performance of Buildings Legislation, assisting with the processing of Property Certificates, and the provision of other technical advice to the Council.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">The Council has Building Control Surveyors located at Lagan Valley Island.\n\nThe office hours are 9.00am to 5.00pm Monday to Friday (excluding Bank and Public Holidays)\n\nTo contact Building Control please contact Tel: 028 9250 9372 or email: building.control@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nTo request an inspection on the same day, place call the office before 10.00am\n\nIf you require an out of hours inspection, please contact us with your request and we will do our best to accommodate you.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Opening Times\nMonday to Friday 9.00am to 5.00pm</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">The administration of the Cemeteries for Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council is undertaken at:\n\nThe Cemeteries Administration Office, Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council, Central Services Depot, Unit. No. 2, Blaris Industrial Estate, Altona Road, Lisburn, BT27 5QB.\n\nThis office deals with the administration issues relating to Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council maintained cemeteries.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Contact\nAdministrator: Mrs Zoe Hamilton\nTel: 028 9260 0813\nEmail: cemetery.office@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Opening Hours\nMonday to Friday 8.30am - 4.30pm\nSaturday 8.30am - 12.30pm\n\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council currently carry out burials in the following cemeteries:\n\nLisburn New Cemetery, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nBlaris Old Graveyard, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nAghalee Graveyard, Aghalee\nTemplecormac Graveyard\nMaghaberry (Friends) Graveyard\n\nLisburn New Cemetery Extension, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nLisburn Cemetery, Hillsborough Road, Lisburn\nPortmore Graveyard\nTrummery Graveyard, Trummery, Moira</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">If you own a dog, you must have a dog licence. If you live within the Council area, you should obtain a licence from the Environmental Health Service. You can obtain it in person, request an application form by post, by telephoning 028 9049 4640 or apply online.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Where can you obtain a dog licence?\n\nIf you own a dog, you must have a dog licence. If you live within the Council area, you should obtain a licence from the Environmental Health Service. You can obtain it in person, request an application form by post, by telephoning 028 9049 4640 or apply online.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Depending on your circumstances the licence costs are:\n£12.50 for unsterilised dogs.\n£32 for a block licence (applicable if you have more than three dogs).\nA breeder’s licence is also available for breeding establishments.\n£5 if your dog is sterilised or you receive an income –related benefit.\nFREE for anyone over 65 for the first dog licence is free and licences for additional dogs are £5.\nThe Department of Agriculture and Rural Development set the dog licence rate.\nYour dog must be microchipped to enable you to be granted a dog licence.</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council is part of ARC21 , a waste management group in Northern Ireland representing 6 councils in the east of the Province. ARC21 works on behalf of its member councils to guide, support and help them meet their legal requirements and drive forward innovative waste management programs.  For more information and to view the ARC21 Waste Management Plan.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">There are three recycling centres within the Council area.  These are located at:\nThe Cutts, Derriaghy, BT17 9HN\nDrumlough, Dromara Road, Hillsborough, BT26 6QA\nCarryduff, 8 Comber Road, BT8 8AN </string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">I had my bin at the collection point from 6:00am on my normal day but it hasn’t been emptied.  Who do I contact?\n\nContact the Council on: 028 9267 3417 or email: opservices.reception@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nMy bin was not collected.\nIf your bin was not collected on the scheduled day, please call the Council on 028 9267 3417 to discuss recollection.  Email: opservices.reception@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nI need assistance with my bin collection.\nThe Council can provide an assisted lift for those households that are unable to put their bin out for collection due to illness or mobility issues. Tel: 028 9250 9453 or email: recycling@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nCan I have a larger bin?\nFamilies can make an application for larger or additional general waste bins if there are six or more permanent residents, or if additional waste is created due to a medical condition.  Tel: 028 9250 9453 or email: recycling@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nHow do I get a recycling bin?\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council will supply bins for collection of dry recyclables and organic food &amp; garden waste (delivery charges and restrictions may apply).  It is every householder’s responsibility to ensure they have a landfill bin; the Council does not sell or supply these bins.</string>

    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Mid East Antrim Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="mideastantrim_councilmenu_Title">Mid East Antrim Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="MEACIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">We would ask that you do not arrive at the council offices without contacting the registrar first. This is to ensure there is a registrar available to answer your queries. Details of how to make an appointment with the registrar service at any of our sites are listed below.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Ballymena \nArdeevin,\n80 Galgorm Road\nBallymena\nCounty Antrim\nBT42 1AB\n(Not County Hall)\nT: 028 2563 3179 or 028 2563 3261\nE: registrar.ballymena@midandeastantrim.gov.uk\n\nCarrickfergus\nCarrickfergus Museum and Civic Centre,\n11 Antrim Street\nCarrickfergus\nBT38 7DG\nT: 028 9335 8224 &amp; 028 9335 8225\nE: registrar.carrickfergus@midandeastantrim.gov.uk\n\nLarne(Part-time opening only)\nSmiley Buildings\nVictoria Road\nLarne\nBT40 1RU\nT: 028 2826 2385\nE: registrar.larne@midandeastantrim.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">When requesting an inspection, sufficient notice must be given to allow Building Regulation to inspect the works.\n\nBuilding Regulation will seek to carry out all requested inspections during the same working day, if the request is made before 10am on that day. Working days are Monday to Friday (excluding public holidays).</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Ballymena \nUnit 10 Galgorm Court\nFenaghy Road\nGalgorm\nBallymena\nBT42 1HW\nT: 028 2563 3356\n\nCarrickfergus\nCivic Centre\n11 Antrim Street\nCarrickfergus\nBT38 7DG\nT: 028 9335 8251</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">When requesting an inspection, please provide the following relevant information. This will assist in processing your request:\nPlan reference number (e.g. FP/2020/123)\nThe address of the works\nSite number (if multi-site application)\nDetails of inspection required\nContact telephone number of a person responsible for the works and will be at the site or property during the inspection</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Your first contact for funeral enquiries is the undertaker who can make all the arrangements for you, including:\nliaising with the council regarding the date and time of burial\nopening a grave or buying a new grave</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Burials can be arranged with the staff at our council offices for cemeteries which are maintained by us.\n\nThe Cemetery Administrator’s Office is closed on Bank and Public Holidays.\nThis does not affect Bank Holiday Interment arrival times, 10.30am to 3.30pm.  (Please see Cemetery Management Rules and Regulations for full details of Opening Hours)</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Grave Subsidence\nGrave subsidence refers to the appearance of graves ‘sinking’. This is an entirely natural process caused by loosened soil settling into place. Grave subsidence is a process that Council manages and rectifies, and it should not be cause for concern. Read more in the Grave Subsidence Information Sheet.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">Before you can license your dog you will need to create an account for Council Direct – follow instructions given on the link below. Residents who previously used Carrickfergus Council’s online dog licensing system their login will still work. There will be other services for residents and businesses added to Council Direct in the near future.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">If you have any problems with the online dog licensing service please contact Kathy McCrossan via \nE: kathy.mccrossan@midandeastantrim.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Applicants will be required to provide evidence in relation to concessions e.g. birth certificate/pension book, proof of income support or housing benefit, or a letter from the vet stating your dog is neutered/sterilised. Your dog licence cannot be issued without providing this proof and failure to do so may result in your licence being void and you may be liable to a maximum £80 fixed penalty.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Missed bin collections may happen due to:\nbad weather conditions\nvehicle breakdown\nas a result of road closures</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Waste Operations on T: 0300 124 5000</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Bins may not be collected for the following reasons:\nLids must be closed.\nThere must be no ropes or cords attached to the bin.\nThe lid and wheels need to be attached and in working order.\nIf your bin is too heavy it cannot be lifted.\nSide waste presented outside the bin will not be collected.\nWrong bin is presented.\nBin contains items of contamination.\nBins should be washed periodically.\nIf your bin has not been collected due to any of the reasons above, a sticker will be placed on the lid and the reason highlighted. To arrange an alternative collection or for further information please contact your local waste operations office.\n\nWaste Operations Offices:\nBallymena	T: 028 2563 3385\nCarrickfergus	T: 028 9335 8267\nLarne	T: 028 2826 2428</string>

    <!--Mid Ulster Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Mid Ulster Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="midulster_councilmenu_Title">Mid Ulster Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="MUCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Mid Ulster Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Mid Ulster Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Registrar registers births, deaths and marriages, and performs marriages and civil partnerships in the Mid Ulster District.</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Cookstown Office, Burn Road, Cookstown\nDungannon Office, Circular Road, Dungannon\nMagherafelt Office, Ballyronan Road, Magherafelt\n\nT: 03000 132 132\nE: registration@midulstercouncil.org\n\nOpening Hours\nThe registration offices are open from:\nMonday to Friday (the Magherafelt office is closed on Wednesdays)\n9.30am to 12.30pm and from 2.00pm to 4.30pm.\n\nAll of the registration offices operate an appointment only system.</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Building Control is responsible for ensuring that Building Regulations are enforced. The standards include requirements on health, structural stability, fire safety, energy conservation and accessibility.\n\nThere is a common confusion among the public between Building Control and Planning.\n\nPlanning is concerned with, among other issues, the siting of the building, its visual impact on the surrounding area and general aesthetics.\n\nFrom April 2015, councils have once again become responsible for Planning and you can find out more about the Mid Ulster District Council Planning Service here.\n\nBuilding Control is concerned with the safety and health, welfare and convenience of people in and around the buildings, the protection of the environment and promotion of sustainable development.</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">To contact the Building Control Service:\nTel: 03000 132 132\nE: buildingcontrol@midulstercouncil.org</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">How do I make an application?\n\nThe application must be submitted to the Council before work starts on site.\n\nWhat fee is payable?\nA ‘plan fee’ is required. Please note the application is not valid unless and until the correct plan fee has been received.  A fee calculator is available here.\n\nWhat happens when an application is submitted?\nWhen a valid application is received this will be assigned to a Building Control Officer. You will receive an ‘acknowledgement of the application, together with confirmation of the name of the Building Control Officer to whom the application has been assigned and the period of time within which we will endeavour to examine the proposals.\n\nThe Building Control Officer will examine the submission to ensure compliance with the relevant building regulations. Where deficiencies are identified amended and/or additional information may be requested. If and when the plans are found to be in compliance with the regulations a ‘Notice of Passing of Building Plans’ will be issued. The approval is valid for a period of three years.\n\nAn inspection fee is payable when work starts on site.\n\nBuilding Control staff will inspect the work as it progresses on site. Notice must be given to the Council at commencement of work and at various stages during the construction.\n\nWhen the work is complete and provided the requirements of the regulations have been met a ‘Completion Certificate’ will be issued.</string>

    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">There are 5 cemeteries maintained by the Council in Mid Ulster.</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Coolhill Cemetery,\nKillyman Road,\nDungannon\nTel: 03000 132 132\n\nCottagequinn Cemetery,\nOld Eglish Road, \nDungannon\nTel: 03000 132 132\n\nDrumcoo Cemetery,\nCoalisland Road, \nDungannon\nTel: 03000 132 132\n\nForthill Cemetery, \nCemetery Road, \nCookstown\nTel: 03000 132 132\n\nPolepatrick Cemetery, \nCastledawson Road,\nMagherafelt\nTel: 03000 132 132</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">N/A</string>

    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">The Council is responsible for dog control issues, including dog licensing, stray dogs, complaints about barking dogs and dog fouling.\n\nThe Council is also responsible for the welfare of certain animals and promotes responsible dog ownership. The related documents section below contains some useful advice on being a responsible dog owner. </string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">The Council Kennels are located at Drumbonaway Dog Kennels and Re-homing Centre. Tel: 028 8773 8861. (You can see some of the typical dogs recused by the Centre on Facebook, search for Mid Ulster Re-homing Centre).</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Statistics\n\nThe Dogs (Northern Ireland) Order 1983 makes provision for the licensing of dogs.  Article 52 of the Order requires Councils to provide information relating to the operating of the Order as required by the Department.  This information is provided by Councils on a quarterly basis, collated and held by the Department.</string>

    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Missed bin collections may happen due to:\nbad weather conditions\nvehicle breakdown\nas a result of road closures</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Ballymacombs Recycling Centre\n\nCastledawson Recycling Centre, \nMoyola Road\n\nClogher Recycling Centre\nFintona Road\n\nCoalisland Recycling Centre,\nDerry Road\n\nCookstown Recycling Centre, \nMolesworth Road\n\nMoneymore Recycling Centre, \nMoneyhaw Road\n\nDrumcoo Recycling Centre, \nCoalisland Road, \nDungannon\n\nFivemiletown Recycling Centre, \nScreeby Road\n\nMaghera Recycling Centre,\nStation Road Industrial Estate\n\nMagherafelt Recycling Centre, \nBallyronan Road (adjacent to Council offices)\n\nDraperstown Recycling Centre, \nWorkplace Industrial Estate, \nMagherafelt Road\n\nTullyvar Recycling centre,\nTullyvar Road, Aughnacloy</string>
    <string name="MUCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">We have 12 centres for recycling and disposing of household waste.\n\nThey are all free to use (please note, charges apply for commercial waste where it is accepted).\n\nPlease note that the last admission to recycling centres is 10 minutes before closing time.</string>


    <!--Newry, Mourne & Down Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Newry, Mourne & Down Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="newrymournedown_councilmenu_Title">Newry, Mourne and Down Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="NMDCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Newry, Mourne & Down Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Newry, Mourne & Down Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Registrar registers births, deaths, marriages and performs marriages and civil partnerships in the Newry, Mourne and Down district.\nCouncil Registration Offices\n\nOpening Hours:\nMonday to Friday: 9.30am - 4.00pm\nClosed for lunch: 12.30pm - 2.00pm</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Oifig An Iúir\nNewry Office, Town Hall\nBank Parade\nNewry BT35 6HR\nTelephone: 028 3026 1512\nEmail: registration@nmandd.org\n\nOifig Dhún Pádraig\nDownshire Civic Centre, Downshire Estate\nArdglass Road\nDownpatrick BT30 6GQ\nTelephone: 0300 013 2233\nEmail: registration@nmandd.org</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Local councils, through their Building Control Service, have a statutory duty to apply the Building Regulations. These are a set of construction requirements and they include regulations on structural stability, fire safety, energy conservation, accessibility and standards on health.\n\nThe role of Building Control includes assessing your plans and inspecting work at various stages as it is being built.\n\nAlthough Building Regulations are a regulatory function of Council, and enforcement forms part of our business, our job is to provide a courteous, equitable and efficient service valued by all of our customers.</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Oifig an Iúir,\nNewry Office,\nO’Hagan House,\nMonaghan Row,\nNewry BT35 8DJ \n\nOifig Dhún Pádraig,\nDownpatrick Office,\nDownshire Civic Centre,\nDownshire Estate, Ardglass Road\n\nTelephone: 0300 013 2233</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Any building works, structural alterations or a change of use require a Building Control Application:\nFull Plans\nBuilding Notice\n\nIf work has already been completed without the submission of a Full Plans or a Building Notice application, this work is called unauthorised work and a Regularisation is legally required.</string>

    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">N/A</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">N/A</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">N/A</string>

    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">All dogs, with the exception of guide dogs, must have a valid licence.  A licence is valid for 12 months.\n\nIf you keep a dog without a licence you can be issued with an £80 fine.\n\nA dog must be microchipped before a licence can be issued. Your local vet can provide more information on microchipping.</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Contact Details\nTelephone: 0300 013 2233\nEmail: ehealth@nmandd.org</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">N/A</string>

    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Newry, Mourne and Down District Council has three different coloured bins for the separate collection of household waste. The blue/green and brown bins are for recycling and the black is for non-recyclable waste.</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Ballykine HRC, Ballynahinch.\n\nBann Road HRC, Castlewellan. Telephone: 028 4377 2891\n\nCamlough HRC, Quarter Road, Camlough. Telephone: 028 3083 7352\n\nCloonagh Road HRC, Downpatrick. Telephone: 028 4483 9884\n\nCrossmaglen, Newry Road, Crossmaglen. Telephone: 028 3086 0777\n\nHilltown HRC, Rostrevor Road, Hilltown. Telephone: 028 4063 8408\n\nKilkeel HRC, Ballymageogh Road, Kilkeel. Telephone: 028 4176 9485\n\nNewry HRC, Chapel Road, Newry. Telephone: 028 3083 3699\n\nNewtownhamilton HRC, Newry Road, Newtownhamilton. Telephone: 028 3087 8014\n\nWarrenpoint HRC, Upper Dromore Road, Warrenpoint. Telephone: 028 4175 2952\n\nIf you need any further information, please contact:\n\nWaste Department Customer Services Section\nTelephone: 0300 013 2233\nEmail: info@nmandd.org</string>
    <string name="NMDCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Council provides assisted lifts for householders who for medical reasons have difficulty in putting their bin out for collection. This service is subject to regular review.\n\nIn exceptional circumstances, householders can request additional waste capacity. For this to occur the household must have six or more residents or a member of the household with a medical condition which generates extra waste. These services are subject to regular review</string>


    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Antrim & Newtownabbey Council Website - Things to do-->
    <string name="antrimnewtownabbey_touristmenu_Title">Antrim and Newtownabbey Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Antrim Castle Gardens &amp; Clotworthy House</item>
        <item>Ballyrobert Gardens</item>
        <item>Rams Island</item>
        <item>Shanes Castle</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_description_AntrimCastleGardensClotworthyHouse">Antrim Castle Gardens are of the most unique and historically intact gardens in the UK and throughout Ireland.\n\nThe Gardens, which won the Special Award in the 2012 Tranlink Ulster in Bloom competition, and Clotworthy complex offer a beautiful location close to Antrim town centre for a stroll, a coffee or the opportunity to experience a variety of exhibitions.\n\nThey are a complex living museum containing over four centuries of culture and heritage alongside remnants of the Masereene family dynasty.  The original location of Antrim Castle has now been integrated within the wider garden landscape in a contemporary and innovative way.\n\nFor visitors, local, national and international, Antrim Castle Gardens is a destination like no other which is becoming a firm favourite in a short space of time.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_contact_AntrimCastleGardensClotworthyHouse">Antrim Castle Gardens &amp; Clotworthy House, \nRandalstown Road, \nAntrim BT41 4LH  \n\nTel: 028 9448 1338.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_additional_AntrimCastleGardensClotworthyHouse">Use the map below to navigate.</string>

    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_description_BallyrobertGardens">The setting for the garden is a 17th-century landscape, complete with the original cottage, barn and farm layout extending to sixteen acres. Sensitively integrating these elements is a six acre garden containing one of Northern Ireland’s most extensive collections of plants, laid out in intimate settings and sweeping borders to enthral the visitor.\n\nVisitors have the opportunity to relax and enjoy a cup of tea with freshly baked scones and tray bakes in the tea room. Ballyrobert Gardens is also home to a specialist retail nursery which is stocked with a wealth of cottage garden plants.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_contact_BallyrobertGardens">154 Ballyrobert Road, \nBallyclare, \nBT39 9RT \n\nTel: 028 9332 2952</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_additional_BallyrobertGardens"></string>

    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_description_RamsIsland">Ram’s Island is located approximately one mile offshore from Lennymore Bay and Sandy Bay on the eastern shore of Lough Neagh.  It is nearly one mile long by a quarter of a mile wide and is the largest island on Lough Neagh. Notable features of the island are a round tower and the ruins of the O’Neills’ 19th century summerhouse. Its remote wilderness and lost in time qualities make Ram’s Island a pleasant and attractive place to visit. A ferry service is available to take visitors to the island and around Lough Neagh.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_contact_RamsIsland">For further details contact Michael Savage: \n\nT. 07715 368050</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_additional_RamsIsland"></string>

    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_description_ShanesCastle">Apr-Sept visits by appointment only\nAvailable for private parties, special and corporate events.\n\nShanes Castle is the family seat of the ONeills of Clanaboy. The Demesne is one of the most beautiful and well maintained in Ireland. Although the Castle has been in ruins since a fire in 1816, the remaining structure, including a unique Camellia House, is a striking feature on the landscape.\n\nThe ONeill Banshee\n\nIn olden times one of the ONeills went to help McQuillan in one of his warlike raids. On his arrival he saw a cow caught in a thorn tree. As this tree was considered sacred by the fairies, no one would cut a branch to release the poor animal. ONeill however did so and freed her. On his successful return home he found that his daughter, Kathleen, had been carried off by the "wee folk" to the bottom of the Lough. From then onwards when evil threatened a member of the family, her shriek was heard upon the shore and along the ruined walls of the castle. Legend also blames the banshee for the fire, which destroyed Shane’s Castle in 1816.\n\nThe Black Face of Stone\n\nOn one of the eastern walls of Shane’s Castle there is a curious female figurehead, with a sad expression. Some say that this figurehead was brought from the east and is much older than the ruins among which it stands. Folklore states that the ONeill family will come to an end if ever it falls.</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_contact_ShanesCastle">Randalstown Road,\nAntrim\n\nT.028 9442 8216\nE. info@shanescastle.com</string>
    <string name="ANTIM_Spinner_additional_ShanesCastle"></string>


    <!--Ards and North Down Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Ards & North Down Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="ardsnorthdown_touristmenu_Title">Ards and North Down Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANDTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Somme Museum</item>
        <item>Ulster Folk and Transport Museum</item>
        <item>Island Hill</item>
        <item>Exploris Aquarium</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Ards and North Down Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click to call</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_WebDescription">Click to visit the website</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Ards and North Down Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_description_SommeMuseum">The Somme Museum examines Irelands role in the 1st World War with special reference to the cross-community involvement in the 3 local volunteer Divisions: the 10th and 16th (Irish) Divisions and the 36th (Ulster) Division. Guided tours bring the visitor back in time to 1910 where they learn about the Home Rule Crisis, recruiting and training of men and life in the trenches. Reconstructed trenches of the Battle of the Somme in 1916.</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_contact_SommeMuseum">Apr-June and Sept: Mon-Thurs 10am-4pm, Sat 11am-4pm\n\nJul and Aug: Mon-Sat 10am-5pm\n\nOct-Mar: Mon-Thurs 10am-4pm, Sat 11am-4pm\n\nThe Somme Museum is closed on Saturdays in December \n\nAddress\nSomme Museum\n233 Bangor Road\nNewtownards\nCo.Down\nBT23 7PH\n\nTelephone\n028 9182 3202</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_additional_SommeMuseum">Wheelchair access. Audio-visual. Shop. Conference facilities.\n\nFood served 10am - 3pm. Includes light snacks, burgers, sausages, chips, frys, homemade soup, cakes, biscuits and scones. Children’s Menu available.\n\nBooking for groups essential. Take away available. Disabled access – parking, toilet and use of wheelchair. Credit/debit cards accepted. (no euros accepted). Seats 55.\n\nIn 2015 Somme Museum were awarded a Bronze Award in the Green Tourism Business Scheme.</string>

    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_description_UlsterFolkandTransportMuseum">Step back in time in and uncover a way of life from 100 years ago\n\nMake a full day of your visit to the Museum of the Year.  It is Ireland’s most comprehensive heritage museum, including world-class Irish Railway Collection, Road Transport Galleries and interactive Flight Experience.  Don’t miss the permanent Titanic exhibition.\n\nExperience bygone life-styles in Ballycultra, the unique Ulster town reconstructed on 60 acres where costumed guides and craft-workers make you feel at home.  Have a snack in the old railway station buffet and enjoy lunch at Cultra Manor.\n\nThere is a varied programme of events all-year-round, with exciting special seasonal events.</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_contact_UlsterFolkandTransportMuseum">Address\n153 Bangor Road\nCultra\nHolywood\nCo. Down\nBT18 0EU\n\nTelephone\n028 9042 8428</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_additional_UlsterFolkandTransportMuseum">Opening Times\n\nMar - Sept, Tues - Sun 10am-5pm\n\nOct - Feb, Tues - Fri 10am-4pm; Sat and Sun 11am-4pm\n\nClosed Mondays except Bank Holiday Mondays</string>

    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_description_IslandHill">The shore car park overlooks Strangford Lough and is an excellent vantage point for bird watchers.\n\nThis site is situated at the end of the Ringcreevy Road, 3 miles from Newtownards off the Comber Road.  The shore car park overlooks Strangford Lough and is an excellent vantage point for bird watchers.  A path along the edge of the lough leads to a causeway accessible only at low tide, leading to the island.  Island Hill provides magnificent views of the lough. </string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_contact_IslandHill">Address\nIsland Hill\nStrangford\nComber\nCo down\nBT23 5JR</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_additional_IslandHill">Facilities: Public toilets and picnic tables.\n\nOpening Times\nopen all year round</string>

    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_description_ExplorisAquarium">Enjoy tropical fish, a shark tank and reptile area at the newly reopend Exploris\n\nEnjoy a diver’s view of marine life from Strangford Lough to the many coral reefs of the Tropical Oceans and enter the dark depths of the Amazon Rainforest where you will see some of it’s inhabitants. Check out our rehabilitation work with common and grey seals in our nursery pens and outdoor pools and enjoy the playful antics of our resident otters.\n\nDon’t miss our unique open pool talks and revisit your childhood memories of the seaside rock pools in our wonderful Kids Zone.  After you’ve enjoyed all the fun relax for brunch, lunch and coffee with a sweet treat in our Café/Restaurant and pick up a treasure in our gift shop.</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_contact_ExplorisAquarium">Address\nThe Rope Walk\nCastle Street\nPortaferry\nCo. Down\nBT22 1NZ\n\nTelephone\n028 4272 8062</string>
    <string name="ANDTIM_Spinner_additional_ExplorisAquarium">Opening Times\nSummer Opening:\n1 April - 31 October 10am – 6pm (Last Admission 4.30pm)\nWinter Opening:\n1 Nov - 31 March 10am – 5pm (Last Admission 4pm)</string>


    <!--Armagh Banbridge Craigavon Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Armagh Banbridge Craigavon Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="armaghbanbridgecraigavon_touristmenu_Title">Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ABCTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Armagh Planetarium &amp; Observatory</item>
        <item>F.E. McWilliam Gallery</item>
        <item>Armagh County Museum</item>
        <item>Navan Centre &amp; Fort</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Armagh Banbridge Craigavon Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Armagh Banbridge Craigavon Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_description_ArmaghPlanetariumObservatory">Never before has the night sky looked – or sounded – as magnificent as when viewed at Northern Ireland’s only Planetarium. Immerse yourself in a unique experience which is quite simply ‘out of this world’,\nIn the Planetarium’s amazing Digital Theatre you can relax and enjoy a 3-D StarDome show that’s not to be missed. Experience our planet and beyond; touring the night sky, discovering some of the myths behind the star constellations and exploring black holes and cosmic chemistry.\nThe Observatory is located together with Armagh Planetarium in approximately 14 acres of attractive, landscaped gardens known as the Armagh Astropark. The Armagh Observatory, founded in 1789 by Archbishop Richard Robinson, is a modern astronomical research institute with a rich scientific heritage.\n\nOpen all year round during daylight hours, a walk through the Astropark is a stroll through the Universe. The Astropark features a scale model of the Solar System in which every three paces corresponds to 100 million km in space. Close to the main Observatory building are two sundials, historic telescopes and telescope domes, the innovative sonic art installation “aroundNorth” and the Human Orrery, the first of its kind in the world.</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_contact_ArmaghPlanetariumObservatory">Armagh Planetarium\nCollege Hill, Armagh, BT61 9DB\nTelephone: + 44 [0] 28 3752 3689\n\nArmagh Observatory\nCollege Hill, Armagh , BT61 9DG\nTelephone: +44 [0] 28 3752 2928    </string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_additional_ArmaghPlanetariumObservatory">The Armagh Observatory has an important function to promote, preserve, and widen access to its library, archives and museum collection, which represents a very signiﬁcant component of Northern Ireland’s scientiﬁc heritage.\n\nVisitors can access both the collections database and the reference Library database to find reference material on all collections, on the history of the Observatory and its architecture, and on prominent staff.</string>

    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_description_F.E.McWilliamGallery">The F.E. McWilliam Gallery and Studio is dedicated to the memory of sculptor Frederick Edward McWilliam, one of Ireland’s most influential and successful artists. F.E. McWilliam was born in Banbridge on the 30th April 1909. He died in London in 1992 and the executors of his estate donated the sculptor’s studio and its contents to the town of his birth.\n\nFeaturing a permanent display of McWilliam’s work, temporary exhibitions of Irish and international art, a craft shop, café and Banbridge Tourist Information Centre, the F.E. McWilliam Gallery and Studio attracts a wide range of local, national and international visitors. </string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_contact_F.E.McWilliamGallery">200 Newry Road, Banbridge, County Down, BT32 3NB\n\nTelephone: + 44 [0] 28 4062 3322</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_additional_F.E.McWilliamGallery">A Visitor Information Point, gallery staff are on hand at all times to assist the public with information and to respond to enquiries. Group tours and primary and post primary school groups are very welcome. Visits may be arranged by appointment. There is a programme of art and craft workshops for adults and children which run throughout the year.</string>

    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_description_ArmaghCountyMuseum">The oldest county museum in Ireland is set in Armagh’s beautiful Georgian tree lined Mall. Located near the centre of St Patrick’s cathedral city, a visit to Armagh County Museum is an ideal way to experience a flavour of the orchard county.</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_contact_ArmaghCountyMuseum">The Mall East, Armagh, BT61 9BE\n\nT: +44 [0]28 3752 3070 </string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_additional_ArmaghCountyMuseum">The Museum staff aim to ensure that all visitors feel welcome and are keen to help with enquiries.  There is an extensive reference library, rich in local archive material, along with photographic and map collections. With a range of changing exhibitions throughout the year, the Museum is an ideal place to begin and explore the fair county of Armagh. </string>

    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_description_NavanCentreFort">Navan Centre &amp; Fort is a place where myth and reality meet. It is one of Ireland’s most famous and important archaeological sites, the legendary Emain Macha. Legends say that Macha, the ancient goddess of war and fertility, scored the earth with her brooch pin and traced the famous outline of this sacred stronghold of the hero Cu Chulainn, home of the famous Red Branch Knights and Ulster Cycle of tales.\n\nLiving History At Navan – Have you ever wondered about the past? How did people live their lives 2,000 years ago? What were their homes like? How did they survive? What were their daily tasks? Allow our Living History characters to bring these questions to life before your eyes! This memorable and interactive experience takes place in our replica Iron Age dwelling. Sit down by the fire and witness Iron Age life come alive! Enjoy helping the Celts prepare and cook their meals and get your hands dirty in the garden and herb beds.\n\nPrepare yourself for battle and learn the skills to survive as an ancient warrior, or sit and relax and allow your imagination to wander as the great tradition of storytelling is used to pass on some of the history of the area and the great warriors who once lived here!</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_contact_NavanCentreFort">81 Killylea Road, Armagh, BT60 4LD\n\nTelephone: +44 (0) 28 3752 9644\n\nE-Mail: navan@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="ABCTIM_Spinner_additional_NavanCentreFort">Facilities at Navan include:\nA condensed exhibition looking at the background of Navan in a local and national context.\nAudio visual show bringing the myths &amp; legends of the Ulster Cycle to life.\nOutstanding Archaeology Discovery Room where archaeology is brought alive to understand the history of Navan.\nA site self-guided map for your visit to Navan Fort, or weather permitting, a fully guided tour to the site.\n\nGreat fun for the kids includes:\nDressing up in Celtic costumes to experience life as a Celt\nBringing archaeology to life by digging in the archeo-pit to uncover bones, coins or maybe even teeth\nCompleting the Navan Ecology Trail to get a prize at the end\nEnjoying the Archaeology Discovery Room and playing in the outdoor activity area on the massive Wolfhound play piece.\n\n[Activities are available daily from April to September, and all are included in your admission fee]\n\nThe ecology trail has interactive activities that will bring the environmental aspects and the conservation work at Navan to life. There is a bug hotel, living willow structure, listening posts, bird boxes, and viewing hide. This is your chance to get up close to the natural environment.\n\nLearn more about other residents at Navan in the hidden crevices of the walls or under the hedges &amp; stones! Through this project, families can reconnect with nature, learn about the environment and most importantly, have fun. The walk to the Navan Mound has been greatly enhanced with information panels and bronze cast artwork that show the great site in a new dimension. Navan has always been a tranquil and intriguing place for walkers, a place of myth and legend. On your return to the Centre take a seat on one of our beautifully carved benches to view the lovely rich landscape where each tree tells its own tale about local ecology and traditional culture.</string>


    <!--Belfast City Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Belfast City Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="belfastcity_touristmenu_Title">Belfast City Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="BCTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Malone House</item>
        <item>Belfast Castle</item>
        <item>Belfast Zoo</item>
        <item>St George’s Market</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Belfast City Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Belfast City Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_description_MaloneHouse">Located on the site of a 17th century fort, Malone House was built in the 1820s for William Wallace Legge, a rich Belfast merchant who had inherited the surrounding land. A keen landscaper, he designed and planted most of the estates grounds, which remain relatively unchanged today.\n\nWhen Legge died, ownership of Malone House passed to the Harberton family, who lived on the premises from 1868 to 1920. The buildings last owner was William Barnett, who presented Malone House to the city of Belfast in 1946. </string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_contact_MaloneHouse">Malone House\nBarnett Demesne\nBelfast\nBT9 5PB\n\nTelephone: 028 9068 1246\nFax: 028 9068 2197\nEmail: mhreception@malonehouse.co.uk</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_additional_MaloneHouse">Following its presentation to the city, Malone House was leased to the National Trust in the early 1970s. After it was nearly destroyed by a fire in 1976, the building was repaired by the council and reopened in June 1983.\n\nSince then, it has become a major venue for weddings, conferences, social functions and other events, while the surrounding grounds are popular with walkers and cyclists. </string>

    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_description_BelfastCastle">The first Belfast Castle was built by the Normans in Belfast city centre in the late 12th century. A second castle, made of stone and timber, was later constructed by Sir Arthur Chichester, Baron of Belfast, on the same site in 1611.\n\nSadly, the castle burned down almost 100 years later, leaving only street names, such as Castle Place, to mark its location.</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_contact_BelfastCastle">Belfast CastleAntrim Rd,Belfast,AntrimBT15 5GR\nT: 028 9077 6925</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_additional_BelfastCastle">Between 1945 and the 1970s Belfast Castle was a popular venue for wedding receptions, dances and afternoon teas.\n\nIn 1978 the castle closed as part of a £2 million refurbishment programme, overseen by Hewitt and Haslam Partnership architects. It reopened on 11 November 1988 and is now a popular venue for weddings, conferences and other events. </string>

    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_description_BelfastZoo">Our 55 acre site is home to more than 130 species, the majority of which are facing increasing danger in their natural habitats.\n\nWe carry out vital conservation work, both in Northern Ireland and around the world. We take part in global and collaborative breeding programmes, which help to ensure the survival of many species under threat.</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_contact_BelfastZoo">Antrim Road,\nBelfast\nAntrim BT36 7NP\n\nTel: 028 9077 6277 </string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_additional_BelfastZoo">During the 1950s and 1960s, the zoo went into decline.\n\nBy the time the corporations parks committee took control of the site in 1962, restoration was badly needed and work began on the new zoo site in 1974.\n\nSince then our zoo has gone from strength to strength to become a leading conservation zoo which is respected globally for the work which we carry out.\n\nIf you have any questions about the history of Belfast Zoo or if you would like us to send you a Belfast Zoo history information pack, email history@belfastzoo.co.uk or call 028 9077 6277 (extension 229).</string>

    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_description_StGeorgesMarket">St George’s Market is one of Belfast’s oldest attractions. It was built between 1890 and 1896 and is one of the best markets in the UK and Ireland. It has been selected for numerous local and national titles and awards for its fresh, local produce and great atmosphere. It holds a weekly Friday Variety Market, the City Food and Craft Market on Saturdays and the Sunday Market. It also hosts a range of events throughout the year.\n\nSt George’s Market has joined Jamie Oliver in being named the “best in Britain”. The market has recently added to its growing list of accolades when it was named ‘Best Market’ at the annual Observer Food Monthly Awards. The award was earned by readers’ votes.\n\nIt was named the UKs Best Large Indoor Market 2014 by the National Association of British Market Authorities, beating off stiff competition from internationally renowned markets like Spitalfields, Billingsgate and Borough.\n\nSt George’s Market was also voted the nation’s favourite Heritage project in the 2014 National Lottery Awards. They recognise and reward the inspirational impact of National Lottery funded projects across the UK. There are seven categories, reflecting the main areas of Lottery funding: arts, education, environment, health, heritage, sport, and voluntary or charity. St George’s Market beat off six other challengers in a public vote to win the Best Heritage Project. It received a £2,000 cash prize to spend on the project as well as a coveted National Lottery Awards trophy.</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_contact_StGeorgesMarket">\n12 - 20 East Bridge Street\nBelfast\nBT1 3NQ\n\nT: 028 9043 5704</string>
    <string name="BCTIM_Spinner_additional_StGeorgesMarket">2017\nWinter Twilight Market - winner of the VM Christmas Awards 2017: Hospitality sector (Restaurants, Coffee Shops, Travel and Leisure)\nBest Market Attraction - National Association of British Market Authorities</string>


    <!--Causeway Coast Glens Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Causeway Coast Glens Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="causewaycoastglens_touristmenu_Title">Causeway Coast and Glens Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="CCGTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Ballycastle Museum</item>
        <item>Roe Valley Arts and Cultural Centre</item>
        <item>Coast and Countryside</item>
        <item>Joey Dunlop Leisure Centre</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Causeway Coast Glens Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Causeway Coast Glens Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_description_BallycastleMuseum">Ballycastle Museum is housed in the listed 18th century courthouse and market building in the town centre.  Visitors to the Accredited Museum can explore the permanent display of the fascinating history of the Irish Homes Industries Workshop, its role in the 1904 St Louis World Fair and the Arts and Crafts Revival in Ireland.  Highlights also include Bronze Age archaeology, Boyds 18th century Ballycastle  and the magnificent Taise Banner from the first Feis na nGleann in 1904.</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_contact_BallycastleMuseum">59 Castle Street,\nBallycastle BT54 6AS\n\nT: 028 2076 2024</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_additional_BallycastleMuseum">Museum Open: September: Friday &amp; Saturday 10am – 6pm and Sunday 2 - 6pm\n\nOctober – December: Closed for winter.</string>

    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_description_RoeValleyArtsandCulturalCentre">An award-winning arts and conference facility situated at the heart of Limavady town, the centre provides a wonderful arts and heritage events programme throughout the year, including theatre, music, visual arts and crafts, local histories, film, creative learning and outreach activities for all.  It features multi-purpose spaces such as the Danny Boy Auditorium with 238 seating capacity, the O’Hampsey Dance Studio, three exhibition galleries, boardrooms and art workshop rooms. The Centre has Drumceatt Square, an outdoor performance space which functions as Limavady Town Square, a Visitor Information Centre, Gift Shop retailing local and regionally produced quality arts and crafts and a Family Zone which includes a community book swap and dedicated childrens reading area with books and toys. Please come in, sit back, relax and enjoy our free Wi-Fi.</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_contact_RoeValleyArtsandCulturalCentre">24 Main Street, \nLimavady \nBT49 0FJ \n\nT: (028) 7776 0650</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_additional_RoeValleyArtsandCulturalCentre">Limavady Museum  is also based here, allowing visitors to explore the history of Limavady and local area through a programme of temporary exhibitions, talks and workshops. An appointment can be made with Museum Services to explore other parts of the accredited collection.</string>

    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_description_CoastandCountryside">The Causeway Coast and Glens Borough is home to some of the most iconic landscapes in Northern Ireland.  A popular year round visitor destination, it provides multiple opportunities for residents and visitors to enjoy the outdoors. At just under 2000 square kilometres and boasting approximately 125 miles of world famous coastline, the Borough stretches from Lough Foyle in the west to the Glens of Antrim in the east, and from the Causeway Coast and Rathlin in the north to the Sperrins and Bann Valley in the south.\n\nCouncil recognises the value of this landscape and through its Coast and Countryside Unit aims to lead on its development, promotion and management in a responsible and sustainable manner.</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_contact_CoastandCountryside">T: 028 7034 7234</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_additional_CoastandCountryside">District Councils in Northern Ireland have a duty under Section 3 (1) of The Access to the Countryside (NI) Order 1983 to “assert, protect and keep open and free from obstruction or encroachment any public right of way; and for this purpose a district council may institute proceedings in its own name”.  This duty also requires the investigation of alleged public rights of way, to determine whether or not same exists.</string>

    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_description_JoeyDunlopLeisureCentre">Health Suite, 2 Swimming Pools, Spa Pool, Soft Play Centre, Fitness Studio with the latest pulse fitness equipment, Cardio Theatre including 48" television screens, Dance Studio, Sauna and Steam Room.\n\nJoey Dunlop Leisure Centre is a modern leisure centre situated on the Garryduff Road in Ballymoney. As of April 2015 the Leisure Centre is owned and managed by Causeway Coast &amp; Glens Borough Council.</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_contact_JoeyDunlopLeisureCentre">If you would like further information, please contact us at Joey Dunlop Leisure Centre,33 Garryduff Road, Ballymoney BT53 7DB.\n\nT: 02827660260</string>
    <string name="CCGTIM_Spinner_additional_JoeyDunlopLeisureCentre"></string>


    <!--Derry Strabane Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Derry Strabane Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="derrystrabane_touristmenu_Title">Derry and Strabane Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="DSTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Alley Arts and Conference Centre</item>
        <item>Guildhall</item>
        <item>Tower Museum</item>
        <item>The Foyle Maritime Festival</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Derry Strabane Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Derry Strabane Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_description_AlleyArtsandConferenceCentre">The Alley Arts and Conference Centre is a state of the art theatre complex, art gallery and conference centre based in the heart of Strabane, County Tyrone.\n\nOffering top class entertainment, arts development and conference facilities, the Alley Arts and Conference Centre is now recognized as one of the leading arts and conference venues within the North West of Ireland.</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_contact_AlleyArtsandConferenceCentre">1a Railway Street\nStrabane\nCo.Tyrone\n\nT: 028 71 384444</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_additional_AlleyArtsandConferenceCentre">The Alley Arts and Conference Centre Box Office and Visitor Information Centre is open Monday - Saturday 10am - 4.30pm and one hour before evening performances until 9.30pm\n\nThe Alley Art Gallery is open Monday - Saturday 10am - 5pm and on evenings of performances</string>

    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_description_Guildhall">The Guildhall is one of Derry’s most recognisable landmarks and has been at the heart of city life since 1890.\n\nAs well as being home to the Council’s chamber and Mayor’s Parlour, the Guildhall is a must see visitor destination where you can be sure of a warm welcome.\n\nWhile visiting the Guildhall you can see the stunning stained glass windows, an exhibition on the Plantation of Ulster, visit the main hall and organ or enjoy refreshments in the cafe.</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_contact_Guildhall">Guildhall St. \nDerry-Londonderry\nNorthern Ireland \nBT48 6DQ \n\nTel: 028 7137 6510  \nEmail: guildhall@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_additional_Guildhall">ACCESSIBILITY\n\nThe following access provision is available in the Guildhall:\nExternal ramp at front of building\nPlatform lift at rear entrance/exit\nInternal lift to first floor\nAccessible toilets are located on ground and first floor</string>

    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_description_TowerMuseum">The award winning Tower Museum is located within the city’s historic walls.  The museum also boasts the only open air viewing facility in the heart of the city centre with stunning panoramic views of the city and River Foyle.</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_contact_TowerMuseum">Tower Museum\nUnion Hall Place\nDerry~Londonderry\nBT48 6LU\n\nTel: 028 7137 2411\nFax: 028 7136 6018\n\nEmail: tower.reception@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_additional_TowerMuseum">ACCESSIBILITY\nThe following access provision is available in the Tower Museum\nLevel access at main entrance\nInternal lift to all 5 levels of Armada Shipwreck – La Trinidad Valencera exhibition including viewing area of city \nInternal lift to museum services area – access to research facilities &amp; genealogy service\nLevel access to learning area \nAccessible toilets are located on ground floor\n\nPlease note that due to the care of the museum collection some areas of the museum are subject to low light levels.</string>

    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_description_TheFoyleMaritimeFestival">The Foyle Maritime Festival returns to Derry~Londonderry from 14th – 22nd July 2018 and will host the stopover of the Clipper Race 2017-18 as they near the end of their Round the World Journey.\n\nQueens Quay will once again be transformed into a maritime wonderland full of fun, activities, music, arts and crafts as we prepare to welcome the Clipper Race yachts back!</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_contact_TheFoyleMaritimeFestival">98 Strand Road, Derry, BT48 7NN\n\nT: (028) 7125 3253</string>
    <string name="DSTIM_Spinner_additional_TheFoyleMaritimeFestival"></string>


    <!--Fermanagh and Omagh Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Fermanagh and Omagh Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="fermanaghomagh_touristmenu_Title">Fermanagh and Omagh Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="FOTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Enniskillen Castle Museums</item>
        <item>Strule Arts Centre</item>
        <item>The Ardhowen</item>
        <item>Marble Arch Caves Global Geopark</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Fermanagh and Omagh Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Fermanagh and Omagh Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_description_EnniskillenCastleMuseums">Enniskillen Castle, situated beside the River Erne in County Fermanagh, was built almost 600 years ago by the ruling Gaelic Maguires. Guarding one of the few passes into Ulster, it has been strategically important throughout its history. Today, the historic site houses two museums, Fermanagh County Museum and The Inniskillings Museum.</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_contact_EnniskillenCastleMuseums">Fermanagh County Museum, \nEnniskillen Castle Museums, \nEnniskillen, \nCo Fermanagh, \nN. Ireland, \nBT74 7HL</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_additional_EnniskillenCastleMuseums">Admission into the Visitor Centre (Visitor Information Centre, Shop, Castle Café, Discovery Space, Fermanagh Genealogy Centre) is FREE. Entry into Enniskillen Castle Museums is detailed below:\n\nThe admission rates below are valid until 31 March 2018:\nAdult: £5.00\nChild: £3.50 \nStudent/Senior Concession: £3.50\nFamily (2 Adults + 3 Children): £13.50 </string>

    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_description_StruleArtsCentre">Strule Arts Centre is an award-winning contemporary arts venue and conference centre that is home to theatre performances, comedy, music, dance, workshops, exhibitions and so much more. With state of the art facilities and stunning views, Strule Arts Centre is the perfect setting to host any event, conveniently located in the heart of Omagh close to transport links and town centre parking. The facility features a 384 seat auditorium, lecture theatre, visual arts gallery, museum exhibitions, dance studio, workshop space, art studio, meeting rooms, café and bar.</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_contact_StruleArtsCentre">Strule Arts Centre\nTownhall Square\nOmagh\nCo. Tyrone\nBT78 1BL</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_additional_StruleArtsCentre">All the information you need about Strule Arts Centre to plan your visit. Information on purchasing tickets, getting to the venue, exhibitions, the Roof Top Museum and much more. If you can’t find what you are looking for drop us an email at strulearts@fermanaghomagh.com or give us a call 028 8224 7831, we are always happy to help.</string>

    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_description_TheArdhowen">Ardhowen Theatre is a theatre in Enniskillen, County Fermanagh, Northern Ireland. It was opened in 1986 and is run by Fermanagh District Council.</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_contact_TheArdhowen">97 Dublin Road,\nDerrychara,\nEnniskillen,\nCo. Fermanagh,\nBT74 6FZ</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_additional_TheArdhowen">GENERAL TERMS AND CONDITIONS\n\nPatrons are advised that tickets cannot be exchanged or refunded. The Ardhowen reserves the right to offer special discounted ticket prices at any time. Reservations held for more than 4 days which have not been paid for will be automatically deleted from the system.\n\nThe use of cameras or recording equipment (visual and audio) is strictly prohibited in The Ardhowen. Mobile phones must be switched off during performances. The Ardhowen is a non-smoking facility.\n\nEvent details are correct at the time of going to print. We reserve the right to alter the programme (including venue seating arrangements) in the event of unforeseen circumstances.\n\nA copy of the full terms and conditions is available from Box Office.</string>

    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_description_MarbleArchCavesGlobalGeopark">Originally employing only a handful of staff the Marble Arch Caves enjoyed a great deal of success and quickly expanded its facilities to accommodate ever growing numbers of visitors.  In 1998 the adjacent Cuilcagh Mountain Park was opened on the northern slopes of Cuilcagh Mountain,fulfilling a vital conservation responsibility for the endangered blanket bog, but also providing a welcome recreational resource, with safe access to the summit of Cuilcagh Mountain.</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_contact_MarbleArchCavesGlobalGeopark">Marble Arch Caves Global Geopark\n43 Marlbank Road\nLegnabrocky\nFlorencecourt\nCounty Fermanagh\nNorthern Ireland BT92 1EW</string>
    <string name="FOTIM_Spinner_additional_MarbleArchCavesGlobalGeopark">THE GEOPARK NETWORK\nThe Global Geoparks Network (GGN) is currently made up of 127 UNESCO Global Geoparks in 35 countries across the world.\n\nIt provides a platform for cooperation and exchange between experts and practitioners in geological heritage and its protection, education and sustainable development. Through cooperation with  Global Geoparks Network partners, important local and national geological sites gain worldwide recognition and benefit from the exchange of knowledge and expertise with other UNESCO Global Geoparks, and improve the quality of the UNESCO Global Geoparks label.\n\nUNESCO and the GGN develop models of best practice and set quality standards for territories that integrate the preservation of geological heritage into strategies for regional sustainable economic development. Members of the GGN are committed together and join in common projects to raise the quality standards of all products and practices of a UNESCO Global Geopark. By working together across borders, UNESCO Global Geoparks contribute to increasing understanding among different communities and as such contribute to not only economic development, but also to peace-building processes. Visit the UNESCO website for more information.</string>


    <!--Lisburn and Castlereagh Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Lisburn and Castlereagh Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="lisburncastlereagh_touristmenu_Title">Lisburn and Castlereagh Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="LCTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Dundonald International Ice Bowl</item>
        <item>Island Arts Centre</item>
        <item>Irish Linen Centre and Lisburn Museum</item>
        <item>Lagan Valley Island</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Lisburn and Castlereagh Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Lisburn and Castlereagh Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_description_DundonaldIceBowl">Welcome to Dundonald International Ice Bowl\nEnjoy a great day out at Dundonald International Ice Bowl with a host of fantastic activities all under one roof!\n\nYou can choose to go ice skating at Northern Ireland’s only public Olympic size ice rink, become king of the lanes in the 30 lane state of the art bowling centre with spectacular glow in the dark Xtreme sessions or go wild for the adventure and excitement of the Indiana Land play kingdom.\n\nIt’s the perfect venue for a family day out, birthday party, group outing or corporate event with a range of exciting activities for adults and children.</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_contact_DundonaldIceBowl">111 Old Dundonald Road, \nBelfast\nBT16 1XT, \nNorthern Ireland   \n\nT: 028 9080 9100</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_additional_DundonaldIceBowl">Safeguarding\n\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council has developed a Child and Adults at Risk Safeguarding Policy, which applies to all employees, elected members, volunteers, contractors, grant-aided organisations and those using our facilities irrespective of their function, remit or role. It can be accessed by clicking here</string>

    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_description_IslandArtsCentre">ISLAND is a triumph of design, technical development and construction, offering arts presenters and the people of Northern Ireland a choice of venues and services to suit every need.\n\nOpened in June 2001, ISLAND has earned the excellent reputation as one of Ireland’s major leading multi-arts venues. ISLAND proudly presents a unique diversity of arts and entertainment choices all year round and is Lisburn City Council’s visually stunning arts base for Lisburn’s vibrant cultural and creative scene.\n\nJoin over 280,000 visitors a year who visit ISLAND and experience the expectation and excitement of live theatre performances, music, dance and children’s’ theatre from Northern Ireland’s top performers, and an array of national and international companies.\n\nBursting at the seams with creativity, ISLAND Arts Centre runs a year round firstclass programme of diverse classes and workshops including visual and verbal arts, community arts, performing arts and a full education programme that actively encourages people of all abilities to explore and preserve our arts heritage.</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_contact_IslandArtsCentre">ISLAND Arts Centre\nThe Island\nLISBURN\nBT27 4RL\n\nInformation T: 028 92 509 509\nBox Off T: 028 92 509 254\nText Phone T: 028 92 509 508</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_additional_IslandArtsCentre">Safeguarding\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council has developed a Child and Adults at Risk Safeguarding Policy, which applies to all employees, elected members, volunteers, contractors, grant-aided organisations and those using our facilities irrespective of their function, remit or role</string>

    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_description_IrishLinenCentreandLisburnMuseum">Originally a museum focusing on the local history of Lisburn and the Lagan Valley, the museum expanded in 1994 with the opening of the Irish Linen Centre.\n\nThe Museum aims to collect, safeguard and interpret artefacts and information relating to the Irish linen industry and the history of the Lagan Valley.\n\nExplore Ireland’s industrial heritage in the Museum’s award-winning exhibition ‘Flax to Fabric: the Story of Irish Linen’. Trace the history of linen production in Ulster, from the earliest times to the present, and see live spinning and weaving demonstrations. The Irish Linen Centre &amp; Lisburn Museum’s galleries also feature a range of temporary and visiting exhibitions, featuring: the history of Lisburn, and its people; local artists, from Blackshaw to Mcloy; textile and linen display; local poets, writers and personalities.</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_contact_IrishLinenCentreandLisburnMuseum">Market Square,\nLisburn,\nBT28 1AG\n\nPhone: +44 28 9266 3377</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_additional_IrishLinenCentreandLisburnMuseum">Safeguarding\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council has developed a Child and Adults at Risk Safeguarding Policy, which applies to all employees, elected members, volunteers, contractors, grant-aided organisations and those using our facilities irrespective of their function, remit or role.</string>

    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_description_LaganValleyIsland">Lagan Valley Island is one of Northern Irelands premier venues. With a unique mix of civic, business and arts facilities, the Centre caters for\nConferences and meetings\nExhibitions\nTheatre events &amp; concerts \nWeddings and banquets.\n\nA striking purpose built venue, Lagan Valley Island caters for up to 402 people, with an extensive choice of rooms available - all with full disabled access.\n\nWe also provide site tours of the facilities here at Lagan Valley Island for large and small groups. These tours need booked in advance.</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_contact_LaganValleyIsland">Lagan Valley Island,\nLisburn,\nCo. Antrim,\nBT27 4RL\nPhone: 028 9250 9292</string>
    <string name="LCTIM_Spinner_additional_LaganValleyIsland">Find Us\nLocated in the heart of Lisburn City in Northern Ireland, Lagan Valley Island is just minutes from the M1 Motorway and just 10 minutes from Belfast City and surrounding areas.\n\nWith 300 free car parking spaces and the train and bus station within walking distance, the venue is extremely accessible to all. The nearby 90-bedroom Premier Inn Hotel offers quality accommodation on our doorstep.</string>


    <!--Mid East Antrim Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Mid East Antrim Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="mideastantrim_touristmenu_Title">Mid East Antrim Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="MEATIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Carrickfergus Castle</item>
        <item>Larne Museum and Arts Centre</item>
        <item>The Gobbins</item>
        <item>Carnlough Beach</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_description_CarrickfergusCastle">Besieged by the Scots, English, Irish and French at various points throughout its history, it has racked up over 750 years of continuous military occupation until 1928, when it was transferred from the War Department to the Ministry of Finance for preservation as an ancient monument. However its days of action were not over. During World War II, it was used as an air raid shelter.\n\nThe castle now houses historical displays as well as cannons from the 17th to the 19th centuries and visitors are encouraged to explore the castle’s large halls and dark corners - there are ramparts, dungeons and even winding staircases with trip steps to deter any invaders.</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_contact_CarrickfergusCastle">Carrickfergus Castle\nMarine Highway\nCarrickfergus\nCounty Antrim\nBT38 7BG</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_additional_CarrickfergusCastle">Additional Information:\nThere is limited disabled access for wheelchair users.\nAll children must be accompanied by an adult.\nNo dogs allowed except guide dogs and assistance dogs</string>

    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_description_LarneMuseumandArtsCentre">The museum is managed by Mid and East Antrim Borough Council, and forms part of the Mid-Antrim Museums Service alongside similar local museums in Ballymena, Carrickfergus and Newtownabbey.\n\nThe Museum is open Monday - Friday, 10.00am - 4.30pm each day.  Admission Free. </string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_contact_LarneMuseumandArtsCentre">Larne Museum &amp; Arts Centre\nMid and East Antrim Borough Council\n2 Victoria Road\nLarne\nBT40 1RN</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_additional_LarneMuseumandArtsCentre">Monday - Friday, 10.00am - 4.30pm\nAdmission free.\n\nSaturday Opening:\nLarne Museum &amp; Arts Centre is currently open on one Saturday per month from 10.00am - 4.30pm.</string>

    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_description_TheGobbins">On the very edge of the Irish Sea lie The Gobbins cliffs. These towering giants cling to the edge of Islandmagee some 20 miles / 32 kilometres north of Belfast on the stunning Causeway Coastal Route. Walking the cliff paths at The Gobbins is an exhilarating adventure that will excite all the senses.</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_contact_TheGobbins">Middle Road, \nIslandmagee \nBT40 3SX, \nUK</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_additional_TheGobbins">How long is the walk?\nThe cliff path itself is accessed by a steep downhill walk for about 1km or 15 minutes walking time. The length of the path itself is about ¾ mile / 1.2km but you will walk this twice as part of your experience. You will also need to be comfortable to walk back up the steep path on your return journey.\n\nWhat should we wear?\nWear outdoor clothing according to the weather, layers are best as it can be windy but as you will be walking you may get warm. Walking shoes or trainers with a flat sole and good treads and a waterproof jacket or poncho are required. Even if it is not raining you are likely to get a splash or two from waves or the resident sea birds!\n\nIs it suitable for children?\nDue to the nature of the attraction and for everyone’s safety and enjoyment there is a height restriction in place similar to those used by some roller coasters. The attraction may not be suitable for most children under the age of 8,  you can phone in advance of booking your visit for further guidance is required.</string>

    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_description_CarnloughBeach">Carnlough is 23km north of Larne just 2km beyond Glenarm. The village has a variety of shops and places to eat. Carnlough Bay is 1.5km wide and at high tide, the sea reaches up to the road  near the village. The sea wall has several accesses down to the sandy beach via steps and a ramp which is suitable for wheelchairs.\n\nAt South Bay car park, a feature of the beach is the beautiful rounded pebbles.There is also a modern play park here.</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_contact_CarnloughBeach">Carnlough\nBallymena \nBT44 0HQ, \nUK</string>
    <string name="MEATIM_Spinner_additional_CarnloughBeach">The southern end of the beach is beyond the high tide line so does not have to be vacated when the tide comes in. Car parking is available alongside the road and also at a car park located next to local shops and public toilets which are just opposite the famous picturesque traditional harbour.</string>


    <!--Mid Ulster Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Mid Ulster Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="midulster_touristmenu_Title">Mid Ulster Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="MUTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Burnavon Arts &amp; Cultural Centre</item>
        <item>Seamus Heaney HomePlace</item>
        <item>Lough Neagh</item>
        <item>Cookstown Leisure Centre</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Mid Ulster Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Mid Ulster Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_description_BurnavonArtsCulturalCentre">The hub for arts, drama, music, theatre and dance in Mid Ulster, the Burnavon stages high quality performances, as well as a varied arts and cultural programme, Irish language activities and a visitor information service.</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_contact_BurnavonArtsCulturalCentre">Burn Rd, \nCookstown \nBT80 8DN</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_additional_BurnavonArtsCulturalCentre">The Burnavon Arts &amp; Cultural Centre, Cookstown is conveniently situated in the heart of Mid Ulster.  The venue is easily accessible from all parts of Northern Ireland and is a short distance away from both the M1 &amp; M2 Motorways.\n\nThere is also FREE parking available in the car park adjacent to the Burnavon.</string>

    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_description_SeamusHeaneyHomePlace">Poet, playwright, translator, lecturer, Nobel Laureate.\n\nListen to the personal stories of family and friends.\nHear how Heaney was valued by influential figures around the world.\nExperience everything from poetry to drama and dance in the  performance space.\nGet creative in our learning zones for children and adults.</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_contact_SeamusHeaneyHomePlace">45 Main Street\nBellaghy\nBT45 8HT\nTelephone: 028 7938 7444\nEmail: seamusheaneyhome@midulstercouncil.org</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_additional_SeamusHeaneyHomePlace">Seamus Heaney was born at Mossbawn on 13 April 1939, near the village of Bellaghy, the eldest of 9 children.\n\nHe attended Anahorish Primary School, before continuing his education from 1951 as a boarder at St Columbs College in Derry.\n\nHe gained a first class honours degree in English Language and Literature from Queens University, Belfast (QUB) in 1961 and it was during this period that his first poems were published in student magazines.\n\nHe went on to qualify as a teacher, taking up a post in St Thomass Secondary School in Belfast before being appointed Lecturer in English at St Josephs College of Education.\n\nIn 1966 his first collection of poems, Death of a Naturalist, was published and in the same year he was appointed to the faculty of QUB as a lecturer in English. He was subsequently a professor at both Harvard University and Oxford University.\n\nHe wrote and published poetry, plays, essays and translations throughout his life and in 1995 he was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature, sealing his reputation as one of Irelands literary greats.\n\nHe died in Dublin in 2013 and chose Bellaghy as his final resting place.</string>

    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_description_LoughNeagh">The largest lake in Ireland and Britain, Lough Neagh borders five counties and captivates visitors with its tranquil atmosphere, un-spoilt scenery, secluded bays and skyward views.\n\nA haven for wildlife and home to a wealth of flora and fauna, the Lough supports thousands of wildfowl and a large-scale eel fishing industry, and also has a rich Christian Heritage with the remnants of three round towers and one of the finest high crosses in the whole of Ireland, Ardboe Cross.</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_contact_LoughNeagh">Lough Neagh Partnership Limited\nUnit 3 The Marina Centre,\n135a Shore Road,\nBallyronan,\nMagherafelt,\nCo. Derry,\nBT45 6JA\n\nT: 028 7941 7941\nE: info@discoverloughneagh.com</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_additional_LoughNeagh">Did you know!\n\nLough Neagh is said to have its very own Atlantis? According to myth the people of one of the kingdoms of ancient Ireland had a magical spring of freshwater.  When the people became greedy the spring rose up and flooded the kingdom, leaving an underwater city beneath the waves of Lough Neagh.</string>

    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_description_CookstownLeisureCentre">From swimming to spinning, Cookstown Leisure Centre has a great range of leisure facilities. Find out what’s on offer for adults, children and families. Our latest programme brochure is on this page and gives detailed information about whats on.\n\nAnd dont forget, you can book online for swimming lessons, squash courts, fitness classes and 10 Pin Bowling!</string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_contact_CookstownLeisureCentre">Cookstown Leisure Centre\n78 Fountain Road\nCookstown, BT80 8QF\n\nT: 028 8676 3853\nE: leisure@midulstercouncil.org </string>
    <string name="MUTIM_Spinner_additional_CookstownLeisureCentre">Ask at reception for a ‘Drop In’ Loyalty Card. Attend any of our Drop In Classes and bank yourself a free swim via use of the Drop-in Loyalty Card. On completion of 6 Drop In Classes treat yourself to your next Drop In Class free or alternatively enjoy a free session in the Health Suite.​</string>


    <!--Newry, Mourne, Down Tourist Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Newry, Mourne, Down Council Website - Things To do-->
    <string name="newrymournedown_touristmenu_Title">Newry, Mourne and Down Tourist Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="NMDTIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Newry and Mourne Museum</item>
        <item>Maghera Church And Round Tower</item>
        <item>FE McWilliam Gallery and Studio</item>
        <item>Dundrum Heritage Trail</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Newry, Mourne, Down Tourist Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nAbout</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nGet in touch</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_CallDescription">Click the phone to call us.</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nWhere are we?</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Newry, Mourne, Down Tourist Menu Information Text-->
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_description_NewryandMourneMuseum">Newry and Mourne Museum first opened in 1986 in Newry Arts Centre and moved to larger premises at Bagenal’s Castle in March 2007. It has welcomed visitors from all over the world who have enjoyed the rich tapestry of this region’s history on display throughout the building.\n\nBuilt in the environs of the site of a 12th century Cistercian abbey, Bagenal’s Castle is an early example of a fortified residence.\n\nThe Castle’s exact location was lost over the years due to constant adaptation of the building, not least when the premises were purchased by Arthur McCann Ltd in 1894 and converted into a bakery.\n\nRediscovered in 1996 when McCann’s sold the site, the Castle has been sympathetically restored.  During the restoration process, drawings from a survey of the Castle completed c.1570 allowed archaeologists to uncover many original features of the Castle and these have been interpreted for the visitor.\n\nThe main exhibitions in the Museum include prehistoric material, Newry as a merchant town, the working life of the area and modern experiences of living in a Border area. Changes are made to the main exhibitions on an annual basis.</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_contact_NewryandMourneMuseum">Newry and Mourne Museum\nBagenals Castle\nCastle Street\nNewry BT34 2BY\n\nTelephone: 028 3031 3182\nEmail: museum@nmandd.org</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_additional_NewryandMourneMuseum">There are plenty of events and activities for young and old on offer throughout the year, including family arts and crafts, a vibrant lecture series, craft workshops, a free tour every Sunday and much more.\n\nThere are also child friendly activities throughout the Museum, including interactives, a comic and costumes that children can try on, which bring history to life.\n\nThe wide range of activities on offer means there is something on offer for all visitors to Newry and Mourne Museum.</string>

    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_description_MagheraChurchAndRoundTower">Maghera Church and Round Tower is of major historical importance and is among many important heritage sites throughout County Down.</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_contact_MagheraChurchAndRoundTower">Carrigs Road\nNewcastle\nCounty Down\nBT33 0JT\n\nT: (028) 9082 3207</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_additional_MagheraChurchAndRoundTower">Opening times\nOpen access all year round.\n\nPrices\nAdmisison free.\n\nDirections from Town\n2 miles (3.2km) north-north-west of Newcastle in Carnacavill townland, beside the Church of Ireland parish church. Gated drive from road leads to car park at church.</string>

    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_description_FEMcWilliamGalleryandStudio">The F.E. McWilliam Gallery and Studio is dedicated to the memory of Banbridge-born sculptor Frederick Edward McWilliam, one of Ireland’s most influential and successful artists. Frederick Edward McWilliam was born in Banbridge on the 30th April 1909. He died in London in 1992 and the executors of his estate donated the sculptors studio and its contents to the town of his birth. The Gallery and studio houses the collection in a superb exhibition facility of Gallery, sculpture garden and reconstructed studio. It also provides café, craft shop and a tourist information point.\n\nGallery Talks and Tours\nGallery staff are on hand at all times to assist the public with information and to respond to enquiries. Group tours may be arranged by appointment.\n\nSchool Visits\nPrimary and post primary groups are very welcome. Visits may be arranged by appointment.\n\nQuails at the Gallery \nQuails offer the award-winning and high quality foods for which this family-run business is renowned. The café is open Monday to Saturday from 09:30 until 17:00 (Lunch served 12:00 - 15:00. Last serving 16:30)\n\nCrafts at the Gallery \nThe gallery showcases beautifully handcrafted products made by talented designers and craftspeople including a wide range of jewellery, ceramics, fashion accessories and other gifts.\n\nThere are various art and craft workshop for adults and children which can be found on the website.\n\nIn 2015 the F.E. McWilliam Gallery and Studio were awarded a Silver Award in the Green Tourism Business Scheme.</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_contact_FEMcWilliamGalleryandStudio">F.E. McWilliam Gallery and Studio\nKaren McKinstry\n200 Newry Road\nBanbridge\nCounty Down\nBT32 3NB\n\nT: (028) 4062 3322</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_additional_FEMcWilliamGalleryandStudio">Location Description\nSituated near the Outlet Shopping Village.\n\nDirections from Town\nTake the A26 (Newry Road) heading south. Come to the top of the A26 and take left at first roundabout. Gallery situated below the road on the right-hand side.\n\nOpening times\nMonday - Saturday: 10:00 - 17:00\nSunday (June, July and August only): 13.00 to 17.00\n\nPrices\nAdmission Free</string>

    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_description_DundrumHeritageTrail">The Heritage Trail takes you on a journey through the historic life and times of Dundrum Village and tells the story of the commercial and maritime heritage.\n\nFollow the trail using the Heritage Trail Map which outlines places of interest including:\nDUNDRUM CASTLE\nDUNDRUM HOUSE\nCLOCK HOUSE\nDOWNSHIRE ARMS\nBATH HOUSE\nGATE LODGE\nST DONARDS CHURCH OF IRELAND\nMANOR HOUSE AND STUDIO\nMURLOUGH NATIONAL NATURE RESERVE\nand many more.\n\nCopies of the Dundrum Heritage Trail map are available from Newcastle Visitor Information Centre on the number above.</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_contact_DundrumHeritageTrail">Christine McCormick\nNewcastle Visitor Information Centre\nNewcastle\nCounty Down\nBT33 0AA\n\nE: newcastle.vic@downdc.gov.uk\n\nT: (028) 4372 2222</string>
    <string name="NMDTIM_Spinner_additional_DundrumHeritageTrail">Location Description\nDundrum Village</string>

</resources>