<resources>
    <!--Application Name-->
    <string name="app_name">N.I Local Amenities Application</string>

    <!--Splash Screen Text Strings-->
    <string name="splash_title">N.I Local Amenities Application</string>

    <!--Area Selection Activity Text Strings-->
    <string name="area_Title">Please select an area of N.I</string>
    <string name="area_AntrimNewtownabbey">Antrim &amp; Newtownabbey</string>
    <string name="area_ArdsAndNorthDown">Ards &amp; North Down</string>
    <string name="area_ArmaghBanbridgeCraigavon">Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon</string>
    <string name="area_BelfastCity">Belfast City</string>
    <string name="area_CausewayAndGlens">Causeway Coast and Glens</string>
    <string name="area_DerryCityAndStrabane">Derry City and Strabane</string>
    <string name="area_FermanaghAndOmagh">Fermanagh and Omagh</string>
    <string name="area_LisburnAndCastlereagh">Lisburn and Castlereagh</string>
    <string name="area_MidAndEastAntrim">Mid and East Antrim</string>
    <string name="area_MidUlster">Mid Ulster</string>
    <string name="area_NewryMourneAndDown">Newry, Mourne and Down</string>

    <!--Council Menu Selections-->
    <string name="CouncilOption_CouncilInformation">Council Information</string>
    <string name="TouristInformation_TouristInformation">Tourist Information</string>

    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Antrim & Newtownabbey Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="antrimnewtownabbey_councilmenu_Title">Antrim &amp; Newtownabbey Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Antrim and Newtownabbey Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Responsibilities Include: \n\u25CFRegistering of births, deaths, stillbirths, marriages and civil partnership \n\u25CFIssuing authorities for forthcoming marriages \n\u25CFPerforming civil marriages and civil partnerships \n\u25CFProviding general information about registrations to the public \n\nThese services are overseen by the General Register Office (GRO), which holds the majority of registration information for Northern Ireland.</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Antrim Civic Centre Office \nThe office is located in Antrim Civic Centre, \n50 Stiles Way, \nAntrim \nBT41 2UB \nTel: 028 9446 3113 \n\nMossley Mill Office \nThe office is located in Mossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North, \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5AQ \nTel: 028 9034 0179</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">How certificates are obtained has changed. These can no longer be issued from district registration offices. \n\nTo obtain a Birth, Death, Marriage or Civil Partnership (after the initial registration has been complete) contact: \n\nThe General Register Office \nWeb: www.nidirect.gov.uk/gro \nTel: 0300 200 7890 \n\nIn person:General Register Office, NIRSA, Colby House, Stranmilis Court, Belfast, BT9 5RR \n\nCertificates cost £15 for the first and £8 for each additional copy of the same certificate thereafter. Certificates applied for online or by telephone will be posted out within 5 working days. A priority service is available, however, an extra fee will be charged. Please contact GRO for further information.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Antrim and Newtownabbey Borough Councils Building Control team has a responsibility to protect you and the environment and to ensure equal access for all, irrespective of physical ability. \n\nAlthough our role is to enforce Building Regulations, we also give support and advice to ensure that you can meet your obligations under the Building Regulations. Todays Building Control service is often involved from the conceptual stage of a project, so that expert opinion on Building Regulation matters is incorporated at the outset. \n\nWhether you are replacing your home heating boiler, building an extension or building a house you will be required to submit an application to Building Control. </string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Building Control for Antrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council is located at: \n\nMossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North, \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5QA \nTel: 028 9034 0140 \nFax: 028 9034 0177 \n(Mon-Fri 9am-5pm)</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Arrange an Inspection \n\nWe will endeavour to visit your property for an inspection on the same day as requested if the inspection booking is made with our office before 10am. \n\nImportant Note: An inspection can be booked as soon as your application has been validated.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Antrim and Newtownabbey Cemetery Opening Times: \nApril - September 8:00am - 10:00pm \nOctober to March 8:00am - 7:00pm \n\nAll our cemetery gates will be locked shut at closing time. \n\nOur cemeteries are open 7 days a week, including all public &amp; bank holidays. \n\nCommemorative Programme \nThe purpose of the Commemorative Programme is to provide members of the public or organisations a means to recognize and honour others through a lasting tribute by the purchase of a tree or bench (subject to conditions) dedicated to that special someone to be planted (or installed) in a park or cemetery. The Programme can also be used by organisations or individuals to sponsor a tree or bench. \n\nIf you require any information regarding the commemorative programme please contact the Leisure Administration team on 02890 340061 or at leisureadmin@antrimandnewtownabbey.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Antrim and Newtownabbey Cemetery Office Opening Times \nMonday to Friday 9.00 am - 4.00 pm. \n\nTelephone enquires will be dealt with Monday to Friday from 9.00 am to 5.00 pm. The office will be closed on Bank Holidays and Public Holidays. \n\nAntrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council is responsible for the general management, regulation and control of the following cemeteries and can provide Information on the Purchase of Burial Rights and for arranging burials and administration. \n\nAntrim (Civic Centre) and Newtownabbey (Mossley Mill) Cemetery Offices: \nMonday - Friday: 9:00am-4:00pm \nAntrim Civic Centre: Tel: 028 9446 3113 \nMossley Mill: Tel: 028 9034 0080</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Antrim Cemetery \nMoylena Road \nAntrim \n\nBelmont Cemetery \nBelmont Road \nAntrim \n\nCranfield Cemetery \nCranfield Road \nRandalstown \n\nCrumlin Cemetery \nCrumlin Road, \nCrumlin \n\nDrummaul Cemetery \nCaddy Road \nRandalstown \n\nMilltown Cemetery \nMilltown Road \nAntrim \n\nMuckamore Cemetery \nOldstone Road \nAntrim \n\nUmgall Cemetery \nUmgall Road \nLylehill \nTemplepatrick \n\nTemplepatrick Cemetery \nCastle Upton \nAntrim Road \nTemplepatrick \n\nCarnmoney East \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney East (ONeill Road Extension) \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney Main \nPrince Charles Way \n\nCarnmoney Church Yard \nChurch Road, Carnmoney \n\nBallyclare \nDoagh Road B95, Ballyclare \n\nRashee \nSpringvale Road, off Rashee Road B94, Ballyclare \n\nKilbride \nMoyra Road, Doagh, Ballyclare \n\nMallusk \nPark Road, Mallusk</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">The Dogs (NI) Order 1983 requires all dog owners to possess a valid dog licence which must be renewed on an annual basis. This is an essential part of being a responsible dog owner as the dog must be microchipped before a dog licence can be obtained.  This will help Council Officers and local Vets return lost dogs to their owners. \n\nIt is an offence for any person to keep a dog without having a valid dog licence and a fixed penalty notice for £80 may be issued.  Any person found guilty of such an offence shall be liable, on summary conviction, to a fine not exceeding level 3 (£1000).</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Antrim Civic Centre \n50 Stiles Way \nAntrim \nBT41 2UB \nTel: 028 9446 3113 \n\nMossley Mill \nCarnmoney Road North \nNewtownabbey \nBT36 5QA \nTel: 028 9034 0000</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Our Online Service \nAntrim and Newtownabbey Borough Council have recently introduced Council Direct, a new online service where you can apply for your Dog Licence and renew it online. \n\nAlready using the Online Service? \nResidents within the Borough who previously used the Council’s online facility will still be able to access their Dog Licence information using their previous login username and password for renewal purposes at Council Direct.</string>

    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Antrim Area Residents: \nUse the online Antrim Bin Checker to see when your Black bin is due for collections. \n\nNewtownabbey Area Residents: \nUse the online Newtownabbey Bin Checker to see when your Black bin is due for collections. Black bins and Brown bins for Newtownabbey residents are collected on the same day once a fortnight. \n\nLeave all bins out by 7:00am on day of collection</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Antrim \nNewpark Household Recycling Centre \nNewpark, Orchard Way, Greystone Road, Antrim \nTel: 028 9442 8107 \n\nBruslee \nBelfast Road, Newtownabbey \n\nCrumlin \nCrumlin Household Recylcing Centre \nRailway Yard, off Main Street, Crumlin \nTel: 028 9442 3640 \n\nONeill Road \nONeill Road Recycling Centre \nONeill Road, Newtownabbey \n\nRandalstown \nCraigmore Household Recycling Centre \nClonkeen Road, Off Church Road, Randalstown \nTel: 028 9447 3813</string>
    <string name="ANCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Buy a Bin \n\nCharges: \n240ltr Black Bin £30.00 \n240ltr Black Bin £20.00 (Discounted rate) \n240ltr Black Bin £15.00 (Pensioner rate) \n\n180ltr Black Bin £25.00 \n180ltr Black Bin £15.00 (Discounted rate) \n180ltr Black Bin £12.50 (Pensioner rate) \n\nBrown bin:Free \nBlue bin (Antrim only): Free \nKerbie Box (Newtownabbey only): Free \nTriplestack (Newtownabbey only): only available in designated areas (at present out of stock) \nHome Composter: £9.99 \n\nTo purchase a bin: \nIf you live in the Newtownabbey area call us on 028 9034 0056/57.</string>

    <!--Ards and NorthDown Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Ards & Northdown Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="ardsnorthdown_councilmenu_Title">Ards &amp; North Down Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ANDCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Ards and North Down Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Ards & North Down Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law all births in Northern Ireland must be registered.  You must register your babys birth within 42 days of the date of birth. You can register a birth in any registrars office in Northern Ireland. \n\nBy law all deaths in Northern Ireland must be registered in Northern Ireland.  A death should be registered as soon as possible to allow funeral arrangements to proceed, but no later than five days from the date of death, except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner. You can register a death at any registrars office in Northern Ireland if the death occurred in Northern Ireland. \n\nYou can choose a civil or a religious wedding.  Civil ceremonies are conducted by the registrar and are non-religious. There are some legal and procedural requirements involved. The Registrar and Deputy Registrars can explain this process.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registrars offices in Ards and North Down are in the council offices at: \n\nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT, telephone 028 9127 8003 \n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP, telephone 028 9182 4003 \n\nOpening hours ​\n\nPlease note that from 1st September 2017 the Registrar’s Office located at Bangor Castle and Church Street, Newtownards will be operating an appointment only system. \n\nTo make an appointment at Bangor Castle please ring 0300 013 3333 ext. 40784 \n\nTo make an appointment at Church Street, Newtownards please ring 0300 013 3333 ext. 40720</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registering a birth \nTo register a birth, you need to fill in a birth registration form. \n\nYou also need certain information to fill in the form: \n\u25CFfull name, surname and sex of the baby \n\u25CFdate and place of birth \n\u25CFfull names, addresses, dates of birth and occupations of the babys mother and father \n\nWhen registering a birth, it is important to give accurate information as a registration cannot be easily changed later. \n\nRegistering a death \nTo register a death, you need to fill in a death registration form with information about the person who died.  This form is available at the registrar’s office. \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be:\n\u25CFaged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17) \n\u25CFunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \n\u25CFfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married \n\u25CFof a different sex \n\nYou must also complete a marriage notice form before your ceremony can take place.  A form is available from the council offices at: \nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT. \n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP </string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">The council is responsible for thousands of building control applications and building inspections every year.  In Building Control we assess plans to make sure they comply with regulations.  As work progresses on site we inspect it at key stages.  It is not the function of Building Control to act as a mediation service between applicant and builder; neither is it to provide a site supervision service, nor to provide a warranty for construction work; these services may be obtained from architects, building surveyors, clerks of works and various warranty schemes.  Building Control service can help designers, builders and the public comply with Northern Ireland Building Regulations. \n\nBuilding Control staff also provide other services, such as the control of dangerous buildings and structures, property searches, postal numbering and providing technical advice.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Contact Building Control \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333 \nEmail: buildingcontrol@ardsandnorthdown.gov.uk \nAddress: Town Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Building control application forms \nAnyone intending to carry out works that would require Building Regulations approval is required to submit either a full plans application or a Building notice application (minor domestic works, including extensions not exceeding 10m2, but not including roofspace) together with the appropriate fee. \n\nBuilding Control offer a pre-submission consultation service, where agents can discuss their outline proposals and seek guidance with regard to means of escape, access for people with disabilities and other issues. \n\nFull plans \nIf the full plan route is chosen, you need to submit: \n\u25CFcompleted full plan application form \n\u25CFduplicate copies of plans \n\u25CFlocation map \n\u25CFsite plan \n\u25CFBuilding notice \n\nThe building notice procedure allows work to be carried out without submitting full plans.  It can be used for the following: \n\u25CFsmall extensions of domestic properties up to 10m2. \n\u25CFstructural alterations of domestic properties. \n\u25CFprovision of services or the installation of fittings in connection with the above. \n\u25CFmaterial change of use of a building to the above \n\nYou cannot use a building control notice for: \n\u25CFindustrial or commercial buildings \n\u25CFerection of houses, flats and maisonettes or roofspace conversions with a floor area over 3m2 \n\nRegularisation \nThis is a procedure, which allows work that was completed without the plans and notices required by Building Regulations being lodged with Building Control.  Such work often comes to light during the sale of a property when the owner is asked to produce evidence of approvals.  When the work complies, or is made to comply with the regulations, which were in operation at the time of completion of the unauthorised work Building Control will issue a “Certificate of Regularisation”.  It can be requested for domestic, industrial or commercial work.</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Headstones \nIf you require a headstone to be put in place, contact a headstone memorial sculptor who can make the necessary arrangements with the council regarding the submission of plans to the Cemeteries Administration Office, 2 Church Street, Newtownards for approval. \n\nCremations \nThere is only one crematorium in Northern Ireland, which is located at Roselawn in Belfast and is under the control of Belfast City Council.  In this case your undertaker will advise you as to how to proceed with arrangements. \nRoselawn Cemetery \n127 Ballygowan Road \nBelfast \nBT5 7UD \nTelephone 028 9044 8288</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Your first contact for funeral enquiries is the undertaker who can make all the arrangements for you, including: \n\u25CFliaising with the council regarding the date and time of burial \n\u25CFopening a grave or buying a new grave \n\nBurials are arranged with the staff in the council offices for cemeteries which are maintained by the council. \n\nThe cemeteries administration office address is 2 Church Street, Newtownards and the telephone numbers are 028 9182 4001 or 028 9182 4002.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">There are different places for burial in Ards and North Down: \n\u25CFBallyvester Cemetery (Donaghadee) \n\u25CFComber Cemetery \n\u25CFGreyabbey New Cemetery \n\u25CFLoughview Cemetery (Comber) \n\u25CFKircubbin Cemetery \n\u25CFKirkistown Cemetery \n\u25CFMovilla Cemetery (Newtownards) \n\u25CFWhitechurch Cemetery (Ballywalter) \n\u25CFClandeboye Cemetery \n\u25CFBangor New Cemetery \n\u25CFRedburn Cemetery (Holywood) \n\u25CFPriory Cemetery (Holywood)</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">It is a legal requirement for all dog owners to register their pet. If this is not done fines can be issued. \n\nApply for a dog licence \nYou can apply for a dog licence online, in person, by post or by telephone. \n\nPay online \nYou need to create an online account. Follow instructions for creating an online account.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">In person \nPlease check the details and return the form with the fee in person to our offices: \n\n2 Church Street, Newtownards, BT23 4AP \nTown Hall, The Castle, Bangor, BT20 4BT \nWe cannot issue a dog licence when you apply in person. \n\nPost \nComplete the form below, sign it and return with the appropriate fee to: \n\nArds and North Down Borough Council \n2 Church Street \nNewtownards \nBT23 4AP \n\nTelephone \nTo pay by debit or credit card, telephone Ards and North Down Borough Council: 0300 013 3333, extension number 40401 or 40418 \n\nIf you need additional information, contact the Borough Inspector. \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333, extension 40401 or 40418</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Microchipping \nAll dogs kept in Northern Ireland must be microchipped before they can be licensed. You must provide a microchip number on the application form for a dog licence. We dont accept a dog licence application without a microchip number.This number must be registered at your current address. \n\nTo find out your dogs microchip number: \n\u25CFask your vet to scan your dog \n\u25CFcontact the organisation that inserted the chip \n\u25CFcontact the Neighbourhood Environment Team who can scan the dog. \n\nAll dog owners must hold a valid licence for their dogs. Your dog must also wear an identity tag, with your name, address and contact telephone number. \n\nIf a veterinary surgeon certifies that inserting a microchip would harm your dogs health, you dont need to microchip your dog. You will need to send us a copy of the vet’s certificate. \n\nFor more information, contact Neighbourhood Environment Team: \nTelephone: 0300 013 3333.</string>

    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">The Councils operate roadside recycling schemes for both dry recyclables (blue bins) and food and garden waste (brown bins) and continues to provide extensive facilities at Waste Recycling Centres for recycling a range of materials. \n\nIn addition to the facilities at the Waste Recycling Centres, there are numerous bin bank facilities for recycling glass containers and textiles.</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">N/A</string>
    <string name="ANDCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Reduce pressure on your grey bin by maximising the materials you can recycle in your blue and green or brown bin.  Use your blue bin to recycle certain clean paper, cardboard, aluminium and plastic products as listed below. Use your brown or green bin for food waste and garden waste such as grass clippings, weeds, leaves and tree branches or twigs. You dont need a green and a brown bin as both bins are used to recycle the same materials.</string>

    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Armagh, Banbridge and Craigavon Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="armaghbanbridgecraigavon_councilmenu_Title">Armagh, Banbridge &amp; Craigavon Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="ABCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Armagh, Banbridge & Craigavon Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law all births occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered. This should be done within 42 days of the date of the birth at any District Registrar’s Office in Northern Ireland. \n\nBy law all deaths occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered. This should be done within 5 days from the date the death occurred except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner. \n\nTo get married you must give a minimum of 28 days notice otherwise you may need to postpone your marriage. It is recommended time period is 8 to 10 weeks, however you can give notice up to a year before the date of your marriage.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Armagh Registration Office \nAddress: The Palace Demesne, Armagh, BT60 4EL \nTelephone: 028 3752 9615 \nEmail: jennifer.coulter@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening Hours: by appointment only \nMonday to Thursday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4.30pm \nFriday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4pm \nPlease contact the office by phone or email to arrange an appointment. \n\nBanbridge Registration Office \nAddress The Civic Building, Downshire Road, Banbridge, BT32 3JY \nTelephone: 028 4066 0614 \nEmail: elaine.gilmour@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening hours: by appointment only \nMonday to Thursday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4.30pm \nFriday: 9.30am – 12.30pm and 2pm – 4pm \n\nPlease contact the office by telephone to arrange an appointment. \n\nCraigavon Registration Office \nAddress: Craigavon Civic and Conference Centre, Lakeview Road, Craigavon BT64 1AL \nTelephone: 028 3831 2440 or 028 3831 2441 \nEmail: registrar@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk \nOpening hours: \nYou do not need an appointment, as a queuing system is in operation, however waiting times will vary. \nMonday to Thursday: 9am-12.30pm (last entrance at 12.15pm) and 2pm-4.30pm (last entrance at 4.15pm) \nFriday: 9am–12.30pm (last entrance at 12.15pm) and 2pm–4pm (last entrance at 3.45pm)</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register a birth? \n\nWhere the parents are married: \nThe following people can register a child’s birth: \nThe mother or father of the child \nThe grandmother, grandfather, aunt, uncle of the child who has knowledge of the information required to register the birth \nThe occupier of the premises in which the child was born \nAny person present at the birth \nAny person having charge of the child \n\nWhere the parents are not married to each other: \nThe name of the father will only be recorded on the birth certificate if both parents are in attendance or attend separately to sign the registration. \nIf either parent is unavailable, please contact the Registrar’s Office for further information. \n\nThe following people can also register a child’s birth: \nMaternal grandmother, maternal grandfather, maternal aunt or maternal uncle of the baby who has knowledge of the information required to register a birth \n\nWho can register a death? \nAny relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register \nAny person present at the death \nA person taking care of the funeral arrangements \nThe Executor or Administrator of the deceased’s estate \nThe occupier (governor, matron, superintendent or other Chief Officer) at the time of death of the premises \nA person finding, or taking charge of, the body \n\nLegal requirements \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be: \nAged 18 years old or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either party are aged 16 or 17 years old) \nUnrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \nFree to marry, for example, neither of you are already married or in a civil partnership \nOf a different sex \nCapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of consenting to the marriage</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Most people realise that they may need approval for their proposed building work but don’t always understand the difference between building regulations and planning permission.  You might need one or the other, both, or neither, but you must find out before you start any work. \n\nPlanning is interested in the way our towns, cities and countryside is developed. This includes the appearance of buildings, the use of land &amp; landscaping considerations, highway access and the impact that the development will have on the general environment.  Planning permission is NOT usually required for most internal alterations, for some extensions, some loft conversions or some garages. \n\nBuilding Regulations deal mainly with health and safety matters in the interest of the people who will use the building.  They also include requirements to ensure that fuel and power is conserved and facilities are provided for people, including those with disabilities, to access and move around inside buildings. \n\nIf you are in any doubt about whether you need to apply for planning permission or building regulations approval, please check with us before you start any work.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Our planning office, located at \n\nBridgewater House, \n23a Castlewellan Road, \nBanbridge, \nCo. Down \nBT32 4AX</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">If you are planning to carry out work, check with us before you start to see if you need building regulations approval. \n\nSome work may also require planning permission, so you should also check with our Planning Service before you begin. \n\nThere are 3 ways to apply: \n\u25CFFull plans application – for proposed work to domestic and non domestic \n\u25CFBuilding notice application – for works of a minor nature to domestic properties. \n\u25CFRegularisation application – for work that has already been carried out to a domestic or non-domestic property without getting approval at the time (retrospective approval of unauthorised work)</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Every effort is made to accommodate individual memorial wishes of families, however, it is necessary to ensure that the size and type of memorials are appropriate to their setting. Therefore all memorials (headstones) must be approved by the Cemeteries Office prior to erection, including the proposed inscription. Please note emblems are not permitted on headstones. </string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">We operate and maintain the following cemeteries: \nAghagallon Cemetery, Rock Lane, Aghagallon \nBallynahone Cemetery, Ballynahonemore Road, Armagh \nBanbridge Cemetery, Newry Road, Banbridge \nDonaghcloney Cemetery, Main Street, Donaghcloney \nDromore New Cemetery, Mound Road, Dromore \nDrumadonnell Cemetery, Dromara Road, Ballyroney \nKernan Cemetery, Kernan Hill Road, Kernan, Portadown \nLurgan Cemetery, New Line, Lurgan \nLynastown Cemetery, Bluestone Road, Portadown \nMagheralin Cemetery, Newforge Road, Magheralin \nOld Annaclone Cemetery, Church Hill Road, Annaclone \nSeagoe Cemetery, Seagoe Road, Portadown \nSeapatrick Cemetery, Church Square, Banbridge \nShankill Cemetery, Shankill Street, Lurgan \nThe Orchard Cemetery, Corcreevy Road, Richhill \n\nWe appreciate that preparing funeral arrangements is a difficult time for families and we try to be as helpful as possible during this time.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">When a grave is purchased, the buyers name and address is entered in to the register as the titleholder for the specified plot and they receive a title deed certificate. \n\nThe titleholder of the burial plot is then given the right to up to three internments (burials) per plot.  The purchase of the plot does not mean that the person has purchased the land, only the right to internment. \n\nWe can only accept a request for an internment from the titleholder and can only grant permission to the titleholder for the erection of memorials. \n\nBurial plots cannot be purchased in advance of a death.</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">Everybody who owns a dog must have a dog licence (exceptions apply see below). It is a requirement that dogs are microchipped in order to apply for a dog licence. A microchipping service is provided by your local Vet, please contact them for further information.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">If you need advice or guidance on which dog licence you need, please call 0300 0300 900 or ehealth@armaghbanbridgecraigavon.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">You do not need a license for the following: \n\u25CFa puppy under six months old and kept by the person who was also the keeper of the bitch that gave birth to the puppy \n\u25CFan assistance dog used by a disabled person \n\u25CFa dog kept, and on offer for sale, in a licensed pet shop \n\u25CFa police dog \n\u25CFa dog kept under a block licence, on the premises to which the block licence relates</string>

    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">You can only order ONE of each type of bin. \n\nYou can order a bin by telephone on 0300 0300 900, by calling into any of our depots or through the Bin-Ovation App. \n\nPlease note: you may only leave out one bin of each colour for collection.  Bin crews will not empty unapproved additional bins.  If you already have a bin and wish to order an extra one due to exceptional circumstances you will need to request an additional/larger bin assessment application. For more information click here. \n\nCancellations \nTo cancel your order, call us on 0300 0300 900.</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Armagh: Station Road Industrial Estate, Station Road, Armagh, BT61 7NP \nKeady: Unit 17, Keady Business Centre, Annvale Road, Keady, BT60 2RP \nMarkethill: Unit 5, Markethill Business Centre, Fairgreen, Markethill, BT60 1PW \nTandragee: Madden Road, Tandragee, BT62 2DG \nBanbridge: Scarva Road, Banbridge, BT32 3QD \nDromore: Mossvale Road, Dromore, BT25 1DG \nRathfriland: Iveagh Park  Road, Rathfriland, BT34 5DZ \nPortadown: Fairgreen Recycling Centre, Duke Street, Portadown, BT62 3EX \nLurgan: New Line Recycling Centre, Tandragee Road, Lurgan, BT66 8TA</string>
    <string name="ABCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">If you would like to dispose of large household items, such as a sofa, cooker, bed, washing machine, fridge or freezer, you can request a bulky waste collection. \n\nThere is a non-refundable charge of £6 per lift of up to 3 bulky household items. \n\nWe will lift \nFurniture	table, chairs, suites, beds, cabinets, carpet/lino, TV, \nWhite goods	fridge, freezer, cooker, tumble dryer, washing machine, microwave, \nGarden equipment	lawnmower, garden implements, summer seat, garden tables/chairs \n\nWe won’t lift \nWood	Sheds, fences, skirting boards, architraves, gripper rods, broken up furniture, dog kennels \nMetal	Iron bars, corrugated iron, garage doors, gates \nDIY materials	Bricks, blocks, concrete, pipes, guttering, plasterboard \nFixtures &amp; fittings	Fireplaces, kitchens, bathroom suites, doors, radiators, storage heaters, water cylinders/tanks, heating systems, stair bannisters, windows, slide robes, glass front fires \nOther	Oil tanks, gas cylinders, car parks, concrete coal bunkers, pianos \n\nThe list is not exhaustive and advice on other items can be obtained from calling on 0300 0300 900 .</string>

    <!--Belfast City Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Belfast Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="belfastcity_councilmenu_Title">Belfast City Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="BCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Belfast City Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Belfast City Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">By law, your babys birth must be registered within 42 days of the date of birth. This is free and can be done in any District Registrars office in Northern Ireland. \n\nOur Registrars office is located in Belfast City Hall \n\nBy law, all deaths occurring in Northern Ireland must be registered no later than five days from when the death occurred (except where the matter has been referred to the Coroner). \n\nMarriage notice \nYou must give a minimum of 28 days notice to get married. If you dont give 28 days notice, you may need to postpone your marriage. You can give notice up to a year before the date of your marriage.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Our office opening hours are: \nMonday to Thursday 	9.30am to 4.30pm 	Last entrance to registration is 4.15pm \nFriday	9.30am to 4pm	Last entrance to registration is 3.45pm \nSaturday and Sunday 	Closed \n\nRegistrars office \nBelfast City Hall \nBelfast \nBT1 5GS \n\nPhone: 028 9027 0274</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">How to register a birth \nYou will need to fill in a birth registration form. This is usually completed by the  person registering the birth (normally the childs mother). \n\nWho can register? \nThe mother or father of the baby, if you are a married couple \ngrandfather or grandmother \nuncle or aunt \noccupier of the premises where the baby was born \nany person present at the childs birth \nany person who has charge of the child. \n\nIn the case of a child born to an unmarried couple, the details of the father may be recorded if: \nboth parents attend and sign the registration form together, or \na declaration of paternity is produced\n\nRegistering a death\nWho can register?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceaseds estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nLegal requirements \n\nTo marry in Northern Ireland, you and your partner must be: \naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17) \nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married \nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married \nof a different sex.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">We are responsible for delivering planning functions in Belfast. This involves:\nreceiving and making decisions on the majority of planning applications\nenforcing breaches of planning permission\nmaking tree preservation orders\nprotecting and preserving built heritage\nproducing a local development plan outlining how land should be used and developed in the future.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Our public office, located at 4-10 Linenhall Street, is open from 9am - 5pm, Monday to Friday.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">How we make planning decisions\nThe type, size and complexity of an application will determine how a decision is made. There are three ways in which a decision can be made:\n\nOur Planning Committee will consider all major applications.\nA planning officer has the authority to determine smaller, more straightforward applications.\nAn elected member may request that an application is decided by the Planning Committee, provided they give sound planning reasons for doing so.\nThe Department of the Environment will make decisions that have regional significance.\nOur Scheme of Delegation (PDF - 75KB) sets out full details.\n\nEnforcement\nWe can take enforcement action against breaches of planning controls where:\nbuilding work which needs planning permission is undertaken without approval,\nconditions attached to a planning condition are not complied with, or\nthe use of a building or site is changed without planning permission.\nIf any planning controls are breached, we will investigate. Planning enforcement is a complex area and the legal processes involved can be lengthy and complicated. An instant response or resolution cannot be guaranteed.\n\nFor more information on how we deal with enforcement complaints and our service standards please read our Enforcement Customer Charter.\n\nRequest to speak to committee\nIf you would like to speak to our planning committee about a planning application, please complete the form below. You need to have the application reference number and you must submit the request at least 48 hours before the committee meeting. You can only speak to committee if youve submitted a written response to an application.\n\nOnce we receive your application we will be in touch with more information.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Cemeteries\nBurials can take place in four of our cemeteries - Roselawn, Dundonald, Knockbreda and Belfast City Cemetery.\n\nHeritage project at the City Cemetery\nWith funding from the Heritage and Lottery Fund (NI)’s Parks for People Programme, we’d like to develop a programme to protect, enhance and promote the rich heritage of City Cemetery.\n\nBereavement Services\nOur Bereavement Services Office is located on the Ground Floor, Cecil Ward Building, 4-10 Linenhall Street, Belfast, BT2 8BP.\nOur phone number is 028 9027 0296.\n\nContact our Bereavement Services Office if you have a query about our cemeteries. </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Office opening hours \nMonday and Friday 	8.30am - 4pm \nTuesday, Wednesday and Thursday 	9am - 4pm \nSaturday 	8.30am - 11.30am \n\nTel: 028 9027 0296 \n\nGround Floor \nCecil Ward Building \n4-10 Linenhall Street \nBelfast \nBT2 8BP </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">About our cemeteries \nRoselawn is currently the only cemetery with new burial plots available. \n\nThere are no new grave plots available in either Dundonald or Belfast City Cemetery, but burials can still take place in existing graves.\n\nCremations are conducted at City of Belfast Crematorium.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">All dogs must have a valid licence and wear identification with the name and address of their keeper, either on a tag or engraved on a collar plate. We no longer issue coloured dog tags with new licences; owners must supply the identification themselves.</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">We have moved\n\nOur customer reception has moved to the ground floor of The Cecil Ward Building.\n\nOur new address is:\nDog Wardens\nGround Floor\nThe Cecil Ward Building\n4-10 Linenhall Street\nBelfast\nBT2 8BP</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">You do not need to license your dog if it is:\na puppy under six months old and kept by the person who is also the keeper of the puppys mother,\nan assistance dog used by a disabled person, or\na police dog.</string>

    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Bin and box collections\n\nPlease recycle as much as possible to avoid over-filling your general waste bin.\n\nWe have two types of collection in Belfast:\nIf you have a general waste bin, a recycling bin and compost bin:\nAll bins are collected fortnightly - recycling bin one week, general waste and compost bin the next week.\nIn most cases, your collection day is the same each week.\nIf you have a purple glass recycling box it may be collected on a different day to your wheeled recycling bin.\nIf you have a general waste bin, red and black recycling boxes and a green food waste bin:\nYour general waste bin is collected fortnightly.\nYour recycling boxes and food waste are collected weekly (on the same day).\nYour collection day will be the same day of the week as your general waste collection. </string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">We have four centres you can use for recycling household waste. They are all free to use. Please note, we cannot accept commercial waste.\n\nAlexandra Park Avenue - 180 Alexandra Park Avenue, BT15 3GJ\n\nBlackstaff Way - 1 Blackstaff Way, BT11 9DT\n\nOrmeau - 6 Park Road, BT7 2FX\n\nPalmerston Road - 2-4 Palmerston Road, BT4 1QA</string>
    <string name="BCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Using your bin\n\nPlease remember:\nAlways leave your bin out by 7am, and keep it out until 8pm if it has not been collected.\nLeave it at your bin collection point and return it to your property after collection.\nDont overfill your bin - make sure the lid closes properly.\nDont leave waste next to your bin as we cant collect it and you risk an £80 fine (see exception below).\nIf using a wheelie bin liner, make sure you remove it from the rim of your bin before collection.\nDont put electrical or bulky items in your bin. Instead book a bulky collection.\nKeep your bin clean, disinfected and in good repair.\nDont put waste in or take waste out of a bin you dont own or control.\nWe will only collect one general waste bin per property, unless there are exceptional circumstances, where:\nthere are six or more people living in the property, or\nsomeone with a medical condition in the property requires another bin for their waste.\nRemember, we cant collect side or bagged waste left beside bins or in entries; this is littering and you could be fined £80. </string>

    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Causeway Glens Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="causewaycoastglens_councilmenu_Title">Causeway Coast &amp; Glens Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="CCGCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Causeway Glens Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Information booklets &amp; leaflets are available at the Registration Reception. Forms are available to the Public for Name changes, Adoptions, Re-registrations, Marriage and Civil Partnership Application, Birth and Death registration.\n\nEach office can only provide certificates for a Birth, Death, Marriage or Civil Partnership when you are registering the event.  You can order certificates for previously registered events in one of the following ways:\nOnline: www.nidirect.gov.uk\nTelephone: 0300 200 7890\nPost: Ask a member of staff for an application form\nIn Person: The General Register Office (GRO), Colby House, Stranmillis Court, Belfast BT9 5RR</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Office opening hours are:\nMonday – Friday: 9.30 am – 12.30 pm and 2.00 pm – 4.30 pm (Ballycastle Office open morning only)\n\nBank and Public Holidays excepted.\n\nAn appointments system operates.\n\nContact Details -\nBallycastle:\nSheskburn House, 7 Mary Street, Ballycastle BT54 6QH\nTel 028 2076 2225\nEmail: stephanie.mclaughlin@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nBallymoney:\nRiada House, 14 Charles Street, Ballymoney, BT53 6DZ\nTel: 028 2766 0200\nEmail: janet.mccaughey@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nColeraine:\nCloonavin, 66 Portstewart Road, Coleraine, BT52 1EY\nTel: 028 7034 7034\nEmail: gwyneth.kerr@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\nEmail: elaine.kane@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk\n\nLimavady:\n7 Connell Street, Limavady, Bt49 OHA\nTel: 028 7772 2226\nEmail: monica.anderson@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">GRO holds records from 1845 for non-Roman Catholic marriages and 1 January 1864 onwards for all marriages, births and deaths. \n\nCauseway Coast and Glens Borough Council Registration Offices are located in Ballycastle, Ballymoney, Coleraine and Limavady.</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">If you intend to erect, alter or extend a building, to install services, fittings or works to a building, or to materially change the use of a building, you must first seek approval to do so from your district council.   There are three ways to apply for building regulations approval with a set fee allocated to each:\nFull Plans Submission - for proposed work to dwellings and non-domestic properties\nBuilding Notice Application - for small/minor work to an existing dwelling\nRegularisation Application - for work that has already been carried out to a dwelling or non-domestic property without getting prior approval</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Ballycastle Office\nSheskburn House\n7 Mary Street\nBallycastle\nBT54 6QH\n\nBallymoney Office\nRiada House\n14 Charles Street\nBallymoney\nBT53 6DZ\nTel: 028 2766 0251, 028 2766 0253\n\nColeraine Office\nCloonavin\n66 Portstewart Road\nColeraine\nBT52 1EY\nTel: 028 7034 7252\n\nLimavady Office\n7 Connell Street\nLimavady\nBT49 0HA\nTel:   028 7776 0301</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">The Building Control Department is there to offer you professional help and impartial advice on your project and to answer any queries you may have on regulatory issues.  There are works that are exempt from requiring an application. We can provide confirmation of exemption from the Building Regulations if a request is received in writing together with a fee of £25.</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">The Estates Service is responsible for the operation and upkeep of cemeteries and Old Graveyards.  These facilities are situated at the following locations.  If you have any queries regarding opening hours or facilities, see below for contact details. \n\nInformation on the purchase of grave plots can be obtained from the Registrar of Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages\n\nAgherton Cemetery, Agherton Road, Portstewart\nBallymoney Cemetery, Knock Road, Ballymoney\nBallywillan Cemetery, Magherabuoy Road, Portrush\nColeraine Cemetery, Portrush Road, Coleraine\nEnagh Cemetery, Scroggy Road, Limavady\nKilrea Cemetery, Blackrock Road, Kilrea\nPortstewart Cemetery, Coleraine Road, Portstewart\nRasharkin Cemetery, Finvoy Road, Rasharkin</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Contact Us\nIf you would like further information, please contact us\n\nTel: 028 2766 0200\nEmail: info@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">“Old Graveyards” refer to the graveyards at:\nAghanloo, Limavady\nAgherton Old, Portrush\nAgivey, Coleraine\nArdclinnis, Glenariff\nBallylintagh, Coleraine\nBallywillan, Portrush\nBanagher, Limavady\nBonamargy, Ballycastle\nBovevagh Limavady\nCamus, Coleraine\nDerrykeighan, Ballymoney\nDesertoghill, Garvagh\nGlenariff Road\nGlenullin, Garvagh\nDownhill, Castlerock\nDunluce, Portrush\nKilraughts, Ballymoney\nLayde, Cushendall\nLoughan, Coleraine\nPriory, Limavady\nQueen Street, Ballymoney\nRamoan, Ballycastle\nTamlaght Finlagan, Limavady\nTemplastragh, Port Bradden\nThe Knockans, Ballymoney\nVow, Ballymoney\nWalworth, Limavady</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">If you keep or own a dog you must obtain a licence for the dog from the Council.\n\nYou cannot obtain a licence for the dog unless the dog has been microchipped. You will need to provide this microchip number when applying for a licence.</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">To apply for a licence you will need to visit your local council offices and enquire about this at reception</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Exemptions For Needing a Dog Licence\na puppy under six months old and kept by the person who is also the keeper of the mother that gave birth to the puppy\nan assistance dog used by a disabled person\na police dog</string>

    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">If you have any queries or require further information on Councils recycling services, please e-mail us at recycle@causewaycoastandglens.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">If you wish to purchase a new bin, wheels or axle, please contact your local Council office:-\n\nBallymoney  028 2766 0222\nColeraine     028 7034 3453\nLimavady     028 7776 0305\nMoyle           028 2076 2225</string>
    <string name="CCGCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Causeway Coast and Glens Borough Council operate a fully engineered facility at Craigahulliar Landfill Site, Ballymacrea Road, Portrush, BT56 8NS.\n\nLicensed to take:\nHousehold/Domestic Waste\nCommercial Waste\nIndustrial Waste</string>

    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Derry Strabane Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="derrystrabane_councilmenu_Title">Derry &amp; Strabane Council Information</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="DSCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Derry Strabane Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Welcome to the District Registration Service.  The primary function of the Registration Offices is to register Births, Stillbirths, Deaths, Marriages and Civil Partnerships, to issue authorities for forthcoming Marriages and Civil Partnerships and to officiate at Civil Marriage Ceremonies and Civil Partnership Ceremonies/Registrations, to issue certified copies and give general information to the public about these matters.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Derry/Londonderry Office operate by appointment or customer call-in system at 14 Magazine Street, BT48 6HH. Call us on 02871 376520 or email michelle.duddy@derrystrabane.com\n\nThe Strabane Office OPERATE BY APPOINTMENT ONLY at Council Offices, 47 Derry Road, Strabane, Co Tyrone BT82 8DY. Call us on 02871 253253 Ext 4209 or email michelle.duddy@derrystrabane.com.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Both offices currently open to the public 9:30 a.m. to 12:30 p.m. and 2:00 p.m. to 4:30 p.m, Monday to Friday and carry out Civil Marriage and Civil Partnership Ceremonies outside these hours by prior arrangement.  There is also service provision available out-of-hours for emergency Death Registration.  Please contact your Funeral Director who will advise.</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Building Control has a statutory duty to enforce building regulations to ensure minimum standards of Health &amp; Safety apply to all buildings.\n\nThe main services provided by the Building Control Department are:\nExamination of applications submitted under the Building Regulations (NI) 2012\nInspection of building work on site\nProvision of information for Property Certificate enquiries\nReporting on applications made for Entertainment Licences\nProviding advice on Building Regulations and associated matters.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">For further information and queries contact:\n\nBuilding Control\nTelephone: (028) 71 253253\nEmail: info@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Changes to the Building Regulations regarding Building Notice applications.\nFrom October 31st 2012 a Building Notice application cannot be accepted for the following work:-\n•    The erection of a dwelling\n•    The increase of the floor area of a dwelling by more than 10m2\n•    The creation of a new storey with a floor area greater than 3m2\n•    The conversion of roof space to habitable accommodation\n•    Domestic garages greater than 30m2</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Active Cemeteries Opening Times:\nSpring / Summer (1st May – 30th September)\nMonday to Sunday 8.00 am to 7.00 pm\n\nAutumn Winter (1st October – 30th April)\nMonday to Sunday 8.00 am to 4.30 pm</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">All enquiries relating to Cemeteries/Graveyards to:\n\nCity Cemetery Office,\nGatelodge,\nLone Moor Road,\nDerry\nBT48 9LA\nTel : 028 71362615\nEmail : grainne.murray@derrystrabane.com</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">N/A</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">All dogs, with the exception of guide dogs, must have a valid licence. Before you get a dog or a puppy you MUST get a licence for it. It is against the law not to. A puppy that stays with its mother must have a licence by the age of six months.\n\nIt should be noted that since April 2012 it is no longer possible to licence a dog without including a valid microchip number for your dog. Microchipping is a simple, safe modern identification method which is permanent and cant be removed, so even if someone steals your dog we can still trace it by its microchip.\n\nDogs must also wear an identity disc or tag, stating the owners name, address and contact telephone number.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Dog Control\nDerry City and Strabane District Council\n47 Derry Road\nStrabane\nBT82 8DY\nTel: 028 71253253 \n\nEnvironmental Health Department\nDerry City and Strabane District Council  \n98 StrandRoad,\nDerry Strabane\nBT48 7NN\nTel: 028 71253253  </string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">A dog’s licence offers some proof of ownership. Under the Dogs (NI) Order 1983 as amended, it is a legal requirement that anyone in possession of a dog must hold a valid licence. As the details of dog owner and dog are officially registered with the Council, each owner who registers his or her dog with their local Council is issued with a licence. Owners are reminded that their dog must wear a collar with an identity disc or tag attached to it.  This tag or disc must state the owner`s name, address and contact telephone number.</string>

    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">The black or grey wheeled bin is the general waste bin. It can be used to dispose of general household waste that is not permitted in either the Blue or Brown Bin. Waste from the black bin typically goes to landfill which is expensive and has an impact on the environment, so Council encourage people to recycle as much as possible using our Blue Bin recycling service or Brown Bin / Caddy food waste collection service.\n\nThe blue wheeled bin is for recycling waste. This helps Council make savings on disposing of waste which means we can do more for you and your family, as well as helping the environment.\n\nDerry City and Strabane District Council now offer food waste collection services to households in the Council district. This new service means we spend less money on dealing with food waste and we can spend more on services for you and your family. It will also help the environment by reducing harmful emissions from landfill.</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">DIRECT HELPLINE FOR WASTE &amp; RECYCLING:\nCall (028) 71 374 107\n\nISSUES WITH REFUSE OR BULKY WASTE COLLECTIONS:\nEmail or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 3435\n\nSTREET CLEANSING:\nEmail Street Cleansing  or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6828\n\nENFORCEMENT:\nEmail Enforcement or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6868​\n\nLITTER BINS / DOG BINS / COMMUNITY CLEAN UPS:\nEmail or Call (028) 71 253 253 Ext 6807</string>
    <string name="DSCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Frequently Asked Questions\n\nQ. What if my bin is not serviced?\nA. If council is unable to service your bin because of operational difficulties attempts will be made to collect it within 24 hours of the scheduled collection date – or on the next working day if your collection day is a Friday.\n\nQ. How many bins can each household leave out for collection?\nA. Council, under normal circumstances, will only collect one bin per household.  Council can arrange to collect additional bins where special circumstances apply i.e. those with medical conditions etc.  Further information on additional bins can be obtained by contacting 028 7137 4017.\n\nQ. Will the operative collect, empty and return my bin as I am physically unable to do so?\nA. Council can arrange to collect, empty and return bins for those residents who are physically unable to do so.  Further information on this scheme can be obtained by contacting 028 7137 4107 or by e-mailing brian.mckenna@derrystrabane.com or ian.lamrock@derrystrabane.com\n\nQ. How can I report any difficulties or complaints?\nA. If you experience any difficulty or problems with any aspects of the service provided, you should contact the Customer Support Services at the City Engineers Department on 028 7137 4107 to register your problem or complaint so that the appropriate action can be taken.</string>

    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Fermanagh Omagh Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="fermanaghomagh_councilmenu_Title">Fermanagh &amp; Omagh Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="FOCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Fermanagh Omagh Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">The Registrar’s Office is one of 11 district registration offices in Northern Ireland whose primary function is to register births, deaths, marriages and civil partnerships.\n\nIt also performs civil marriages and partnerships at approved venues and provides general information to the public.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Opening Hours:\nMonday – Thursday 9.30am – 4.30pm\nFriday  9.30am – 4.00pm\nClosed 12.30pm – 1.30pm\n\nIt is advisable to arrive 15 minutes before closure times.\n\nThe registration service for Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is delivered from both the Grange in Omagh, and the Townhall in Enniskillen.\nTelephone:  0300 303 1777</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">Councils in Northern Ireland have a statutory duty to enforce the Building Regulations and they do this through their Building Control Department. The Building Regulations are designed to ensure certain standards of health and safety apply to all buildings, with particular focus on achieving adequate standards of fire safety.  The regulations also protect the environment by requiring buildings to be thermally efficient, reducing energy consumption and therefore the emission of pollutants which damage the atmosphere. Regulations are also in place to deal with accessibility and are effective in improving the quality of life for people with disabilities. Building Regulations and Building Control, therefore, have an important role to play in helping protect people and the environment</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">The Building Control Department, Fermanagh and Omagh District Council\nTel: 0300 303 1777\nEmail: buildingcontrol@fermanaghomagh.com</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council’s Building Control Department provide the following services:\nEnergy Performance in buildings\nPostal naming and numbering\nProperty Certificates\nBuilding Regulations\nDangerous Structures\nEntertainment Licensing\n\nThrough these services the Building Control Department works closely with architects, agents, those involved in construction, members of the legal profession as well as members of the public.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is responsible for five Municipal cemeteries in the District.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">The locations are as follows:-\nCross Cemetery, located adjacent to the Irvinestown Road (but accessible through Carran Industrial Estate) in Enniskillen, BT74 4RN\nGreen Hill Cemetery, Gortin Rd, Omagh BT79 7HT\nFintona Cemetery, Tattymoyle/Lisdergan Rd, Fintona, Co. Tyrone\nBreandrum Cemetery, Tempo Rd, Enniskillen, BT74 6HR\nDublin Rd Cemetery, 112 Dublin Rd, Omagh, BT78 1TT.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Breandrum Cemetery in Enniskillen and the Dublin Rd Cemetery in Omagh are both closed cemeteries. Only new plots for the burial of a child are available for purchase in Breandrum.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">The Dogs (NI) Order 1983 requires all dog owners to possess a valid dog licence which must be renewed on an annual basis. This is an essential part of being a responsible dog owner as the dog must be microchipped before a dog licence can be obtained.  This will help Council Officers and local Vets return lost dogs to their owners.\n\nIt is an offence for any person to keep a dog without having a valid dog licence and a fixed penalty notice for £80 may be issued.  Any person found guilty of such an offence shall be liable, on summary conviction, to a fine not exceeding level 3 (£1000).</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Please visit the website at: https://council.direct/ to register your dog.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Changes in Dog Licensing Legislation regarding Licence Tags\n\nDue to recent changes in Dog Licensing and Identification Regulations, from the 1st January 2015 Dog Licence Tags will be abolished and will not be provided with a Dog Licence.  This decision has been taken by Central Government (DARD) and therefore local Councils must be in full compliance.  It will still however be a legal requirement to have the keeper’s details attached to the collar on a plate or badge.\n\nConcessionary dog licence applications and renewals.\n\nConcessionary dog licence applications cannot be made online as proof of concession must be provided to the Dog Licensing Department before the licence can be issued.  Concessionary Licences for sterilized dogs and persons over 65 licensing their first dog, who have previously provided proof of concession, can be renewed online as the concessionary status will not have changed.</string>

    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Fermanagh and Omagh District Council is responsible for waste management, including refuse collection and bulky waste.\n\nThe Council provides a refuse collection service to all domestic households as well as a collection service to commercial and industrial premises. The Council actively promotes community engagement in the separation of waste at source by utilising the mixed collection service provided by the Council.\n\nWe have state of the art recycling facilities at Drummee outside Enniskillen and Gortrush on the edge of Omagh. In addition there are Recycling Centres in the following locations across the district.</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Alternatively, opening times are as follows:\n· Drummee, Enniskillen: Monday-Friday, 9am-6pm, Saturday, 9am-4pm\n· Gortrush, Omagh: Monday-Friday, 8.30am-6.45pm, Saturday, 9am-6.45pm\n· Belleek: Monday, Wednesday Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-3pm\n· Carrickmore: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Dromore: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Fintona: Monday-Friday, 11am-5.45pm, Saturday 11am-3.45pm\n· Garrison: Tuesday, Thursday 10am-6pm, Saturday 3.30pm-5.30pm\n· Irvinestown: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Kesh: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pmn· Kinawley: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Lisbellaw: Monday, Tuesday Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday, 10am-5.30pm\n· Lisnaskea: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Newtownbutler: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Rosslea: Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Friday, 10am-6pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm\n· Tempo: Monday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, 10am-5.30pm, Saturday 10am-5.30pm</string>
    <string name="FOCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Keep up to date by downloading the Bin-Ovation app\n\nYou can keep up to date by downloading the Bin-Ovation app, a new App that is revolutionising recycling for households and local Councils across Northern Ireland.\n\nFree to download, Bin-ovation gives you absolute clarity on how to treat hundreds of household waste items and gives instant access to waste and recycling information.\n\nAvailable on smart phones and tablets the bin-ovation app provides:\nClarity on over 300 household items including which bin the item should be placed in or if you can take it to your local recycling centre\nCalendar and a set reminder of which day your bin is collected to ensure you present the right bin at the kerbside for collection\nOpening hours and GPS directions to your local recycling centres\nNews on your current and new collections including up to date information on daily changes to services\nInformation on your recycling services and tips on how to reduce, reuse and recycle</string>

    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Lisburn Castlereagh Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="lisburncastlereagh_councilmenu_Title">Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="LCCIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Lisburn Castlereagh Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Registration services for Births, Marriages and Civil Partnerships are available at the Councils headquarters at Lagan Valley Island, Lisburn and also at its Council Offices at Bradford Court, Galwally.\n\nIn view of the nature of the services offered, customer demand can be difficult to predict and there may be periods of high demand where customers may be required to wait to see the first available Registrar/Deputy Registrar. We would ask for your patience and understanding in this regard.\n\nTo facilitate the  process, please read over the information which has been compiled to assist you accessing our registration services.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Lisburn Registration Office\nRegistration Office, Island Civic Centre, The Island, Lisburn, BT27 4RL\nTel: 028 9250 9262/3 or 028 9250 9488\nEmail: bdm.registration@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nOpening Hours\nMonday - Friday\n9.00am to 12.45pm\n1.30pm to 4.30pm (Closing at 4.00pm on the first Wednesday of each month)\n\nYou do not need an appointment to visit Lisburn Registration Office, though please note that a queuing system is in operation. Customers should arrive at least 45 minutes before the stipulated closing times. However Registration Staff deal with very sensitive issues and waiting times will vary.\n\nPlease note Mondays and Fridays are extremely busy days and longer waiting times may apply.  On occasions you may be asked to return.  If your visit to the Lisburn Office is not urgent you may prefer to call on a Tuesday, Wednesday or Thursday.\n\nCastlereagh Registration Office\nCastlereagh Registration Office is now operating an appointment system.  To make an appointment please use the contact details below.\n\nRegistration Office, 1 Bradford Court, Upper Galwally, Castlereagh, BT8 6RB\nTel: 028 9244 7822 or 028 9250 9270\nEmail: RegBradfordCourt@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nOpening Hours\nMonday - Friday\n9.30am to 12.30pm\n2.00pm to 4.30pm (closes 4.00pm on Friday)</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">The aim of the Building Control Service is to deliver a customer orientated quality service to architects, designers, developers, builders, solicitors and the general public, and as such ensure a safer and healthier built environment for all.\n\nAs well as enforcing the application of The Building Regulations, the Building Control Service has a responsibility for Street Naming, Dangerous Buildings legislation, Energy Performance of Buildings Legislation, assisting with the processing of Property Certificates, and the provision of other technical advice to the Council.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">The Council has Building Control Surveyors located at Lagan Valley Island.\n\nThe office hours are 9.00am to 5.00pm Monday to Friday (excluding Bank and Public Holidays)\n\nTo contact Building Control please contact Tel: 028 9250 9372 or email: building.control@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nTo request an inspection on the same day, place call the office before 10.00am\n\nIf you require an out of hours inspection, please contact us with your request and we will do our best to accommodate you.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">Opening Times\nMonday to Friday 9.00am to 5.00pm</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">The administration of the Cemeteries for Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council is undertaken at:\n\nThe Cemeteries Administration Office, Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council, Central Services Depot, Unit. No. 2, Blaris Industrial Estate, Altona Road, Lisburn, BT27 5QB.\n\nThis office deals with the administration issues relating to Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council maintained cemeteries.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Contact\nAdministrator: Mrs Zoe Hamilton\nTel: 028 9260 0813\nEmail: cemetery.office@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Opening Hours\nMonday to Friday 8.30am - 4.30pm\nSaturday 8.30am - 12.30pm\n\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council currently carry out burials in the following cemeteries:\n\nLisburn New Cemetery, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nBlaris Old Graveyard, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nAghalee Graveyard, Aghalee\nTemplecormac Graveyard\nMaghaberry (Friends) Graveyard\n\nLisburn New Cemetery Extension, Blaris Road, Lisburn\nLisburn Cemetery, Hillsborough Road, Lisburn\nPortmore Graveyard\nTrummery Graveyard, Trummery, Moira</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">If you own a dog, you must have a dog licence. If you live within the Council area, you should obtain a licence from the Environmental Health Service. You can obtain it in person, request an application form by post, by telephoning 028 9049 4640 or apply online.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">Where can you obtain a dog licence?\n\nIf you own a dog, you must have a dog licence. If you live within the Council area, you should obtain a licence from the Environmental Health Service. You can obtain it in person, request an application form by post, by telephoning 028 9049 4640 or apply online.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Depending on your circumstances the licence costs are:\n£12.50 for unsterilised dogs.\n£32 for a block licence (applicable if you have more than three dogs).\nA breeder’s licence is also available for breeding establishments.\n£5 if your dog is sterilised or you receive an income –related benefit.\nFREE for anyone over 65 for the first dog licence is free and licences for additional dogs are £5.\nThe Department of Agriculture and Rural Development set the dog licence rate.\nYour dog must be microchipped to enable you to be granted a dog licence.</string>

    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Lisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council is part of ARC21 , a waste management group in Northern Ireland representing 6 councils in the east of the Province. ARC21 works on behalf of its member councils to guide, support and help them meet their legal requirements and drive forward innovative waste management programs.  For more information and to view the ARC21 Waste Management Plan.</string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">There are three recycling centres within the Council area.  These are located at:\nThe Cutts, Derriaghy, BT17 9HN\nDrumlough, Dromara Road, Hillsborough, BT26 6QA\nCarryduff, 8 Comber Road, BT8 8AN </string>
    <string name="LCCIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">I had my bin at the collection point from 6:00am on my normal day but it hasn’t been emptied.  Who do I contact?\n\nContact the Council on: 028 9267 3417 or email: opservices.reception@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nMy bin was not collected.\nIf your bin was not collected on the scheduled day, please call the Council on 028 9267 3417 to discuss recollection.  Email: opservices.reception@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nI need assistance with my bin collection.\nThe Council can provide an assisted lift for those households that are unable to put their bin out for collection due to illness or mobility issues. Tel: 028 9250 9453 or email: recycling@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nCan I have a larger bin?\nFamilies can make an application for larger or additional general waste bins if there are six or more permanent residents, or if additional waste is created due to a medical condition.  Tel: 028 9250 9453 or email: recycling@lisburncastlereagh.gov.uk\n\nHow do I get a recycling bin?\nLisburn &amp; Castlereagh City Council will supply bins for collection of dry recyclables and organic food &amp; garden waste (delivery charges and restrictions may apply).  It is every householder’s responsibility to ensure they have a landfill bin; the Council does not sell or supply these bins.</string>

    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu-->
    <!--Information provided by Mid East Antrim Council Website - Resident Information-->
    <string name="mideastantrim_councilmenu_Title">Mid East Antrim Council Services</string>
    <!--Spinner Tool Contents-->
    <string-array name="MEACIM_Spinner_Array_Titles">
        <item>Births, Deaths &amp; Marriages</item>
        <item>Building Control</item>
        <item>Cemeteries</item>
        <item>Dogs</item>
        <item>Waste &amp; Recycling</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu Placeholder Text-->
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaDescriptionHeading">\nDescription</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaDescription">Description</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaContactHeading">\nContact</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaContactDescription">Contact Information</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaAdditionalHeading">\nAdditional</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_activity_AreaAdditionalDescription">Additional Information</string>
    <!--Mid East Antrim Council Menu Council Information Text-->
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_BirthsDeathsMarriages">We would ask that you do not arrive at the council offices without contacting the registrar first. This is to ensure there is a registrar available to answer your queries. Details of how to make an appointment with the registrar service at any of our sites are listed below.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Ballymena \nArdeevin,\n80 Galgorm Road\nBallymena\nCounty Antrim\nBT42 1AB\n(Not County Hall)\nT: 028 2563 3179 or 028 2563 3261\nE: registrar.ballymena@midandeastantrim.gov.uk\n\nCarrickfergus\nCarrickfergus Museum and Civic Centre,\n11 Antrim Street\nCarrickfergus\nBT38 7DG\nT: 028 9335 8224 &amp; 028 9335 8225\nE: registrar.carrickfergus@midandeastantrim.gov.uk\n\nLarne(Part-time opening only)\nSmiley Buildings\nVictoria Road\nLarne\nBT40 1RU\nT: 028 2826 2385\nE: registrar.larne@midandeastantrim.gov.uk</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_BirthsDeathsMarriages">Who can register births?\nthe mother or father of the baby (if married to each other)\nthe father and mother (if unmarried)\n\nIf the mother or father are unable to register the birth, the following are also qualified to register the birth:\ngrandfather, grandmother, uncle or aunt (please check with the Registrar)\noccupier of the premises where the baby was born\nany person present at the child’s birth\nany person who has charge of the child.    \n\nWho can register a death?\nany relative of the deceased who has knowledge of the details needed to register\na person present at the death\na person taking care of the funeral arrangements\nthe executor or administrator of the deceased’s estate\nthe governor, matron or chief officer of a public building where the death occurred\na person living in and responsible for a house, lodgings or apartments where the death occurred\na person finding, or taking charge of, the body.\n\nCouples marrying in Northern Ireland have a choice of either a religious or civil ceremony. The initial arrangements are the same for both types of marriage. It is important to organise the date and time of your marriage as soon as possible.\n\nYou and your partner must be:\naged 18 or above on the day of your wedding (consent is needed if either of you is aged 16 or 17)\nunrelated to one another in a way that would prevent you from getting married\nfree to marry, for example, neither of you is already a civil partner or legally married\nof a different sex\ncapable of understanding the nature of a marriage ceremony and of agreeing to marriage.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_BuildingControl">When requesting an inspection, sufficient notice must be given to allow Building Regulation to inspect the works.\n\nBuilding Regulation will seek to carry out all requested inspections during the same working day, if the request is made before 10am on that day. Working days are Monday to Friday (excluding public holidays).</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_BuildingControl">Ballymena \nUnit 10 Galgorm Court\nFenaghy Road\nGalgorm\nBallymena\nBT42 1HW\nT: 028 2563 3356\n\nCarrickfergus\nCivic Centre\n11 Antrim Street\nCarrickfergus\nBT38 7DG\nT: 028 9335 8251</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_BuildingControl">When requesting an inspection, please provide the following relevant information. This will assist in processing your request:\nPlan reference number (e.g. FP/2020/123)\nThe address of the works\nSite number (if multi-site application)\nDetails of inspection required\nContact telephone number of a person responsible for the works and will be at the site or property during the inspection</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_Cemeteries">Your first contact for funeral enquiries is the undertaker who can make all the arrangements for you, including:\nliaising with the council regarding the date and time of burial\nopening a grave or buying a new grave</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_Cemeteries">Burials can be arranged with the staff at our council offices for cemeteries which are maintained by us.\n\nThe Cemetery Administrator’s Office is closed on Bank and Public Holidays.\nThis does not affect Bank Holiday Interment arrival times, 10.30am to 3.30pm.  (Please see Cemetery Management Rules and Regulations for full details of Opening Hours)</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_Cemeteries">Grave Subsidence\nGrave subsidence refers to the appearance of graves ‘sinking’. This is an entirely natural process caused by loosened soil settling into place. Grave subsidence is a process that Council manages and rectifies, and it should not be cause for concern. Read more in the Grave Subsidence Information Sheet.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_Dogs">Before you can license your dog you will need to create an account for Council Direct – follow instructions given on the link below. Residents who previously used Carrickfergus Council’s online dog licensing system their login will still work. There will be other services for residents and businesses added to Council Direct in the near future.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_Dogs">If you have any problems with the online dog licensing service please contact Kathy McCrossan via \nE: kathy.mccrossan@midandeastantrim.gov.uk.</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_Dogs">Applicants will be required to provide evidence in relation to concessions e.g. birth certificate/pension book, proof of income support or housing benefit, or a letter from the vet stating your dog is neutered/sterilised. Your dog licence cannot be issued without providing this proof and failure to do so may result in your licence being void and you may be liable to a maximum £80 fixed penalty.</string>

    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_description_WasteRecycling">Missed bin collections may happen due to:\nbad weather conditions\nvehicle breakdown\nas a result of road closures</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_contact_WasteRecycling">Waste Operations on T: 0300 124 5000</string>
    <string name="MEACIM_Spinner_additional_WasteRecycling">Bins may not be collected for the following reasons:\nLids must be closed.\nThere must be no ropes or cords attached to the bin.\nThe lid and wheels need to be attached and in working order.\nIf your bin is too heavy it cannot be lifted.\nSide waste presented outside the bin will not be collected.\nWrong bin is presented.\nBin contains items of contamination.\nBins should be washed periodically.\nIf your bin has not been collected due to any of the reasons above, a sticker will be placed on the lid and the reason highlighted. To arrange an alternative collection or for further information please contact your local waste operations office.\n\nWaste Operations Offices:\nBallymena	T: 028 2563 3385\nCarrickfergus	T: 028 9335 8267\nLarne	T: 028 2826 2428</string>











</resources>
